<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/escollections.sh</path>
		<name>ES Collections</name>
		<desc>This script will dynamically create the custom collections game list file.

WARNING: This script only works if your ROMS are named according to the EmuMovies/HyperSpin/LaunchBox naming standard.

When ran, it will scan your various roms folder looking for the games that belong to the collection chosen.  The script will create or update the Emulation Station custom gamelist file that is used by the collections menu items to show the games for it.

You do not have to add the custom collection prior to running the script.

Run the script and generate the collection of your choice then restart Emulation Station.

After restarting, enable the new collection via the GUI.

Press Start to bring up the menu
Choose GAME COLLECTION SETTINGS
Choose CUSTOM GAME COLLECTIONS

Enable the new collection and exit back out to the main menu.  The new collection should now appear on the main menu.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/escollections.png</image>
		<playcount>7</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20180108T142118</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/esgamelist.sh</path>
		<name>ES Gamelist Utility</name>
		<desc>This script is for installing premade, prescraped Emulation Station gamelist.xml files.  The script also provides a cleanup utility to audit existing gamelist.xml files against existing rom files to end up with a gamelist.xml file only containing entries for matching rom files.

The premade gamelist files are setup for No Intro filenames like EmuMovies, Hyperspin, Launchbox. They are also setup to use the four folders for PNG/MP4 media.
boxart
cart
snap
wheel

The premade gamelist files contain multiple entries per game to account for all known filename extensions supported by the particular system.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/esgamelist.png</image>
		<playcount>16</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20180123T120945</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/removemedia.sh</path>
		<name>Media Removal Utility</name>
		<desc>This utility will remove any media files (boxart, cartart, snap, wheel) that exists that does not hvae a matching rom file.

This utility will only work if you are using the following folder structure.

boxart  - boxart images
cartart - cartart image
snap    - video snaps
wheel   - marquee or wheel images

You can select individual systems to remove excess media files.</desc>
		<image>./icons/removemedia.png</image>
		<playcount>9</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20180123T121507</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/bezels.sh</path>
		<name>Retroarch Bezels</name>
		<desc>This script will enable or disable the use of bezel overlays for Retroarch based emulators.

Bezel overlays and config files are here:
/opt/retropie/configs/all/retroarch/overlay

Retroarch config files are here:
/opt/retropie/configs/(emulator)/retroarch.cfg

This script will update the retroarch config files to use the designated named bezel config file.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/bezels.png</image>
		<playcount>21</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20180203T162331</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/gpioshutdown.sh</path>
		<name>GPIO Shutdown Utility</name>
		<desc>The GPIO shutdown script has already been installed on this base image.

This script will allow a momentary pusbutton to power on or power off the Raspberry Pi.

The script is setup to have the pushbutton wired to GPIO pins 5 and 6.

One press will shutdown and one press will power back on.</desc>
		<image>/home/pi/RetroPie/retropiemenu/icons/gpioshutdown.png</image>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/jukebox.sh</path>
		<name>RetroPie Jukebox</name>
		<desc>Turn your RetroPie into a music jukebox.
    
This is the fruitbox jukebox software by 'chundermike'.

Place your MP3 files into the /roms/jukebox folder to have them included. 

There is a userguide.txt file for documentation located here:
/home/pi/rpi-fruitbox-master

You can manually configure your controllers by adjusting the config file located here.
/home/pi/rpi-fruitbox-master/skins/WallJuke/fruitbox.cfg
</desc>
		<image>/home/pi/RetroPie/retropiemenu/icons/jukebox.png</image>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/jukeboxconfigure.sh</path>
		<name>RetroPie Jukebox Configuration</name>
		<desc>Configuration utility for the Fruitbox jukebox.
    </desc>
		<image>/home/pi/RetroPie/retropiemenu/icons/jukeboxconfigure.png</image>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/utilites/armbian-config.sh</path>
		<name>Armbian-Config</name>
		<desc>Change user password, boot options, internationalization, SSH and more.</desc>
		<image>./icons/raspiconfig.png</image>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20180906T025443</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<folder>
		<path>./konami</path>
		<name>Konami Code</name>
		<desc>Konami Code</desc>
		<image>./icons/konami.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20180910T000000</releasedate>
		<developer />
		<publisher />
		<genre />
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</folder>
	<folder>
		<path>./konami/full</path>
		<name>Full Sets</name>
		<desc>Full Sets</desc>
		<image>./icons/full.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20180910T000000</releasedate>
		<developer />
		<publisher />
		<genre />
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</folder>
	<folder>
		<path>./konami/boxart</path>
		<name>Boxart Sets</name>
		<desc>Boxart</desc>
		<image>./icons/boxart.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20180910T000000</releasedate>
		<developer />
		<publisher />
		<genre />
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</folder>
	<folder>
		<path>./konami/hacks</path>
		<name>Hacks</name>
		<desc>Hacks with Boxart</desc>
		<image>./icons/boxart.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20180910T000000</releasedate>
		<developer />
		<publisher />
		<genre />
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</folder>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/BIOS.sh</path>
		<name>BIOS</name>
		<desc>BIOS set.

For IBM PC compatible computers, BIOS (BYOS, an acronym for Basic Input/Output System and also known as the System BIOS, ROM BIOS or PC BIOS) is non-volatile firmware used to perform hardware initialization during the booting process (power-on startup), and to provide runtime services for operating systems and programs. The BIOS firmware comes pre-installed on a personal computer's system board, and it is the first software run when powered on. The name originates from the Basic Input/Output System used in the CP/M operating system in 1975. Originally proprietary to the IBM PC, the BIOS has been reverse engineered by companies looking to create compatible systems. The interface of that original system serves as a de facto standard.

The BIOS in modern PCs initializes and test the system hardware components, and loads a boot loader or an operating system from a mass memory device. In the era of MS DOS, the BIOS provided a hardware abstraction layer for the keyboard, display, and other input/output (I/O) devices that standardized an interface to application programs and the operating system. More recent operating systems do not use the BIOS after loading, instead accessing the hardware components directly.

Most BIOS implementations are specifically designed to work with a particular computer or motherboard model, by interfacing with various devices that make up the complementary system chipset. Originally, BIOS firmware was stored in a ROM chip on the PC motherboard. In modern computer systems, the BIOS contents are stored on flash memory so it can be rewritten without removing the chip from the motherboard. This allows easy, end-user updates to the BIOS firmware so new features can be added or bugs can be fixed, but it also creates a possibility for the computer to become infected with BIOS rootkits. However, a BIOS upgrade that fails can brick the mainboard permanently, unless the system includes some form of backup for this case.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/BIOS.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate />
		<developer />
		<publisher />
		<genre />
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atari2600.sh</path>
		<name>atari 2600</name>
		<desc>Atari 2600 rom set with box art. 

History:
The Atari 2600 (or Atari VCS before November 1982) is a home video game console by Atari, Inc. Released on September 11, 1977, it is credited with popularizing the use of microprocessor-based hardware and ROM cartridges containing game code, a format first used with the Fairchild Channel F video game console in 1976. This format contrasts with the older model of having non-microprocessor dedicated hardware, which could only play the games that were physically built into the unit.

For five years, from 1977 until late 1982, the system was officially sold as the Atari VCS, an abbreviation for Video Computer System. Following the release of the Atari 5200 in November 1982, the VCS was renamed to the "Atari 2600", after the unit's Atari part number, CX2600. The 2600 was typically bundled with two joystick controllers, a conjoined pair of paddle controllers, and a game cartridge: initially Combat,and later Pac-Man. 
</desc>
		<image>./icons/a2600.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19770911T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atari5200.sh</path>
		<name>atari 5200</name>
		<desc>Atari 5200 rom set with box art. 

History:
The Atari 5200 SuperSystem, commonly known as the Atari 5200, is a home video game console that was introduced in 1982 by Atari Inc. as a higher-end complementary console for the popular Atari 2600. The 5200 was created to compete with the Intellivision, but wound up more directly competing with the ColecoVision shortly after its release.

The 5200's internal hardware is almost identical that of Atari's 8-bit computers, although software is not directly compatible between the two systems. The 5200's controllers have an analog joystick and a numeric keypad along with start, pause and reset buttons. The 360-degree non-centering joystick was touted as offering more control than the eight-way joystick controller offered with the Atari 2600. 
</desc>
		<image>./icons/a5200.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840521T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atari7800.sh</path>
		<name>atari 7800</name>
		<desc>Atari 7800 rom set with box art. 

History:
The Atari 7800 ProSystem, or simply the Atari 7800, is a home video game console officially released by Atari Corporation in 1986. It is almost fully backward-compatible with the Atari 2600, the first console to have backward compatibility without the use of additional modules. It was considered affordable at a price of US$140.

The 7800 has significantly improved graphics hardware over the 2600, but uses the same audio chip. It also shipped with a different model of joystick than the 2600-standard CX40.

The 1986 launch is sometimes referred to as a "re-release" or "relaunch" because the Atari 7800 had originally been announced on May 21, 1984, to replace Atari Inc.'s Atari 5200, but a general release was shelved due to the sale of the company. 
</desc>
		<image>./icons/a7800.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atarilynx.sh</path>
		<name>Atari Lynx</name>
		<desc>Atari Lynx rom set with box art. 

History:
The Atari Lynx is a 16-bit handheld game console that was released by Atari Corporation in September 1989 in North America, and in Europe and Japan in 1990. The Lynx holds the distinction of being the world's first handheld electronic game with a color LCD. The system is also notable for its forward-looking features, advanced graphics, and ambidextrous layout. The Lynx competed with the Game Boy (released just 2 months earlier), as well as the Game Gear and TurboExpress, both released the following year. It was discontinued in 1995.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/lynx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/coleco.sh</path>
		<name>ColecoVision</name>
		<desc>ColecoVision rom set with box art. 

History:
The ColecoVision is Coleco Industries' second-generation home video-game console which was released in August 1982. The ColecoVision offered a closer experience to more powerful arcade game systems compared to competitors such as the Atari 2600, along with the means to expand the system's basic hardware.

The initial catalog of twelve games included Nintendo's Donkey Kong as the pack-in cartridge, Sega's graphically impressive Zaxxon, and some lesser known arcade titles that found a larger audience on the console, such as Lady Bug, Cosmic Avenger, and Venture. Approximately 145 titles in total were published as ROM cartridges for the system between 1982 and 1984.

Coleco withdrew from the video game market in 1985, and ColecoVision was discontinued that same year.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/col.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820811T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Coleco Industries</developer>
		<publisher>Coleco Industries</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/fds.sh</path>
		<name>Famicom Disk System</name>
		<desc>Famicom Disk System rom set with box art. 

History:
Famicom Disk System device is connected to the Famicom deck by plugging a special cartridge known as the RAM Adapter into the system's cartridge port, and attaching that cartridge's cable to the disk drive. The RAM adapter contains 32 kilobytes (KB) of RAM for temporary program storage, 8 KB of RAM for tile and sprite data storage, and an ASIC known as the 2C33. The ASIC acts as a disk controller for the floppy drive, and also includes additional sound hardware featuring a single-cycle wavetable-lookup synthesizer. Finally, embedded in the 2C33 is an 8KB BIOS ROM. The Disk Cards used are double-sided, with a total capacity of 112 KB per disk. Many games span both sides of a disk, requiring the user to switch sides at some point during gameplay. A few games use two full disks, totaling four sides. The Disk System is capable of running on six C-cell batteries or the supplied AC adapter. Batteries usually last five months with daily game play. The battery option is due to the likelihood of a standard set of AC plugs already being occupied by a Famicom and a television.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/fds.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860221T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20170627T214550</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gamegear.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA Game Gear</name>
		<desc>SEGA Master System rom set with box art. 

History:
The Game Gear is an 8-bit handheld game console released by Sega on October 6, 1990 in Japan, 1991 in North America and Europe, and Australia in 1992. The Game Gear primarily competed with Nintendo's Game Boy, the Atari Lynx and NEC's TurboExpress. The handheld shares much of its hardware with the Master System and is able to play its own titles as well as those of the Master System, the latter being made possible by the use of an adapter. Containing a full-color backlit screen with a landscape format, Sega positioned the Game Gear as a technologically superior handheld to the Game Boy.

Though the Game Gear was rushed to market, its unique game library and price point gave it an edge over the Atari Lynx and TurboExpress. However, due to issues with its short battery life, lack of original titles, and weak support from Sega, the Game Gear was unable to surpass the Game Boy, selling 10.62 million units by March 1996. The Game Gear was succeeded by the Genesis Nomad in 1995 and discontinued in 1997. It was re-released as a budget system by Majesco Entertainment in 2000, under license by Sega.

Reception of the Game Gear was mixed, with praise for its full-color backlit screen and processing power for its time, criticisms over its large size and short battery life, and questions over the quality of its game library.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/gg.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901006T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gbc.sh</path>
		<name>Game Boy Color</name>
		<desc>Game Boy Color rom set with box art. 

History:
The Game Boy Color is a handheld game console manufactured by Nintendo, which was released on October 21, 1998 in Japan[8] and was released in November of the same year in international markets. It is the successor of the Game Boy.

The Game Boy Color, as suggested by the name, features a color screen, but no backlight. It is slightly thicker and taller than the Game Boy Pocket, which is a redesigned Game Boy released in 1996. As with the original Game Boy, it has a custom 8-bit processor somewhat related to a Zilog Z80 central processing unit (CPU).[9] The original name – with its American English spelling of "color" – remained unchanged even in markets where "colour" was the accepted English spelling.

The Game Boy Color's primary competitors were the much more advanced Neo Geo Pocket by SNK and the WonderSwan by Bandai (both released in Japan only), though the Game Boy Color outsold these by a wide margin. The Game Boy and Game Boy Color combined have sold 118.69 million units worldwide.[1][2] It was discontinued in 2003, shortly after the release of the Game Boy Advance SP.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/GameBoyColor.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19881021T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gb.sh</path>
		<name>Game Boy</name>
		<desc>Game Boy rom set with box art. 

History:
The Game Boy is Nintendo's second handheld system following the Game &amp; Watch series introduced in 1980 and it combined features from both the Nintendo Entertainment System and Game &amp; Watch.[10] It was either bought as a standalone unit or bundled with the puzzle game Tetris.[11]

During its early lifetime, the Game Boy mainly competed with Sega's Game Gear, Atari's Lynx, and NEC's TurboExpress. The Game Boy beat its rivals and became a tremendous success.[12] The Game Boy and its successor, the Game Boy Color,[8] have sold over 118 million units worldwide. Upon the Game Boy's release in the United States, it sold its entire shipment of one million units within a few weeks.[13] The Game Boy and Game Boy Color were discontinued in the early 2000s in favor of the subsequent Game Boy Advance, released in 2001.[14] It is currently the second best-selling hand-held console of all time, the Nintendo DS being the first.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/GameBoy.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890421T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/intellivision.sh</path>
		<name>Intellivision</name>
		<desc>Intellivision rom set box art. 

History:
The Intellivision is a home video game console released by Mattel Electronics in 1979. The name Intellivision is a portmanteau of "intelligent television". Development of the console began in 1977, the same year as the introduction of its main competitor, the Atari 2600. In 1984 Mattel sold the Intellivision business to a former Mattel Electronics executive and investors that would become INTV Corporation. Games development started in 1978 and continued until 1990 when the Intellivision was discontinued. From 1980 to 1983 over 3 million Intellivision units were sold.

In 2009, video game website IGN named the Intellivision the No. 14 greatest video game console of all time. It remained Mattel's only video game console until the release of the HyperScan in 2006.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/intellivision.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19790000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Mattel Electronics</developer>
		<publisher>Mattel Electronics</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/mastersystem.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA Master System</name>
		<desc>SEGA Master System rom set with box art. 

History:
The Sega Master System is a third-generation home video game console that was manufactured by Sega. It was originally released in 1985 as the Sega Mark III in Japan. After being redesigned prior to its North American launch, the console was renamed Master System and released in 1986 in North America, 1987 in Europe, and 1989 in Brazil. The Master System was also released in Japan in 1987 with additional features over the overseas models. Both the Mark III and the original Master System models could play with both cartridges (or "Mega Cartridges", as they were officially called) and the credit card-sized Sega Cards, which retailed at lower prices than cartridges but had lower storage capacity; the Master System II and later models did not have the card slot. The Master System also featured accessories such as a light gun and 3D glasses which were designed to work with a range of specially coded games.

Succeeding the SG-1000, the Master System was released as a direct competitor to the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) in the third generation of video game consoles. The Master System was constructed with hardware superior to that of the NES, but failed to overturn Nintendo's significant market share advantage in Japan and North America. However, it attained significantly more success in Europe and Brazil. The hardware of the Master System also shared many similarities with Sega's handheld game console, the Sega Game Gear. Compared to its competition from Nintendo, the Master System's game library lacks a number of well-received titles due to Nintendo's licensing practices that restricted third-party developers from creating games for any system other than the NES. Sales of the console have been estimated between 10 and 13 million units, not including recent Brazil sales, compared to 62 million NES units sold. Reception to the system given in retrospect lends credit to the console's role in Sega's development of the Sega Genesis, as well as for having a number of well-received titles, particularly in PAL regions, but is generally critical of its small game library. As of 2015, the Master System is the longest-lived game console (30 years and continuing), due to its popularity in Brazil.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sms.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19851020T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/megadrive.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA MegaDrive/Genesis</name>
		<desc>SEGA MegaDrive/Genesis rom set with box art. 

History:
The Sega Genesis, known as the Mega Drive in most regions outside of North America, is a 16-bit home video game console which was developed and sold by Sega Enterprises, Ltd. The Genesis was Sega's third console and the successor to the Master System. Sega first released the console as the Mega Drive in Japan in 1988, followed by a North American debut under the Genesis moniker in 1989. In 1990, the console was distributed as the Mega Drive by Virgin Mastertronic in Europe, by Ozisoft in Australasia, and by Tectoy in Brazil. In South Korea, the systems were distributed by Samsung and were known as the Super Gam*Boy, and later the Super Aladdin Boy.

Designed by an R&amp;D team supervised by Hideki Sato and Masami Ishikawa, the hardware was adapted from Sega's System 16 arcade board, centered on a Motorola 68000 processor as a primary CPU and a Zilog Z80 as a secondary processor. The system supports a library of more than 900 games created both by Sega and a wide array of third-party publishers and delivered on ROM-based cartridges. It can play Master System games when the separately sold Power Base Converter is inserted. The Genesis has benefited from several peripherals and network services, as well as multiple first-party and third-party variations of the console that focus on extending its functionality.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/megadrive.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19881029T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/megadrive-japan.sh</path>
		<name>Sega Megadrive Japan</name>
		<desc>Sega Megadrive Japan rom set with box art. 

History:
Sega first released the console as the Mega Drive in Japan in 1988, followed by a North American debut under the Genesis moniker in 1989. In 1990, the console was distributed as the Mega Drive by Virgin Mastertronic in Europe, by Ozisoft in Australasia, and by Tectoy in Brazil. In South Korea, the systems were distributed by Samsung and were known as the Super Gam*Boy, and later the Super Aladdin Boy.

Designed by an R&amp;D team supervised by Hideki Sato and Masami Ishikawa, the hardware was adapted from Sega's System 16 arcade board, centered on a Motorola 68000 processor as a primary CPU and a Zilog Z80 as a secondary processor. The system supports a library of more than 900 games created both by Sega and a wide array of third-party publishers and delivered on ROM-based cartridges. It can play Master System games when the separately sold Power Base Converter is inserted. The Genesis has benefited from several peripherals and network services, as well as multiple first-party and third-party variations of the console that focus on extending its functionality.

In Japan, the Mega Drive did not fare well against its two main competitors, Nintendo's Super Famicom and NEC's PC Engine, but achieved considerable success in North America, Brazil and Europe. Contributing to its success were its library of arcade game ports, the popularity of the Genesis-exclusive Sonic the Hedgehog series, several popular sports game franchises, and aggressive youth marketing that positioned the system as the cool console for adolescents. The release of the Super Nintendo Entertainment System two years after the Genesis resulted in a fierce battle for market share in the United States and Europe that has often been termed as a "console war" by journalists and historians.[2][3] As this contest drew increasing attention to the video game industry among the general public, the Genesis and several of its highest-profile games attracted significant legal scrutiny on matters involving reverse engineering and video game violence. Controversy surrounding violent titles such as Night Trap and Mortal Kombat led Sega to create the Videogame Rating Council, a predecessor to the Entertainment Software Rating Board.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/megadrive_art_blur.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega Enterprises, Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Sega Enterprises, Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/nes.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo Entertainment System</name>
		<desc>NES rom set with box art. 

History:
The Nintendo Entertainment System (commonly abbreviated as NES) is an 8-bit home video game console that was developed and manufactured by Nintendo.

The best-selling gaming console of its time, the NES helped revitalize the US video game industry following the video game crash of 1983. With the NES, Nintendo introduced a now-standard business model of licensing third-party developers, authorizing them to produce and distribute titles for Nintendo's platform.

It was initially released in Japan as the Family Computer (Hepburn: Famiri Konpyuta) (also known by the portmanteau abbreviation Famicom (Famikon) and abbreviated as FC) on July 15, 1983, and was later released in North America during 1985, in Europe during 1986, and Australia in 1987. In South Korea, it was known as the Hyundai Comboy (Hyeondae Keomboi) and was distributed by SK Hynix which then was known as Hyundai Electronics. It was succeeded by the Super Nintendo Entertainment System.

In 2009, the Nintendo Entertainment System was named the single greatest video game console in history by IGN, in a list of 25. It was judged the second greatest console behind the Sega Dreamcast in PC Magazine's "Top 10 Video Game Consoles of All Time".
</desc>
		<image>./icons/nes.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19851018T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/ngpc.sh</path>
		<name>Neo Geo Pocket Color</name>
		<desc>Neo Geo Pocket Color rom set with box art. 

History:
TThe Neo Geo Pocket Color (also stylized as NEOGEOPOCKET COLOR, often abbreviated NGPC), is a 16-bit color handheld video game console manufactured by SNK. It is a successor to SNK's monochrome Neo Geo Pocket handheld which debuted in 1998 in Japan, with the Color being fully backward compatible. The Neo Geo Pocket Color was released on March 16, 1999 in Japan, August 6, 1999 in North America, and on October 1, 1999 in Europe, entering markets all dominated by Nintendo.

After a good sales start in both the U.S. and Japan with 14 launch titles (a record at the time) subsequent low retail support in the U.S.,lack of communication with third-party developers by SNK's American management, the craze about Nintendo's PokÈmon franchise, anticipation of the 32-bit Game Boy Advance, as well as strong competition from Bandai's WonderSwan in Japan, led to a sales decline in both regions
</desc>
		<image>./icons/ngp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19990806T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/ngp.sh</path>
		<name>Neo Geo Pocket</name>
		<desc>Neo Geo Pocket rom set with box art. 

History:
The Neo Geo Pocket is a monochrome handheld game console released by SNK. It was the company's first handheld system and is part of the Neo Geo family. It debuted in Japan in late 1998 but never saw a western release, being exclusive to Japan and smaller Asian markets such as Hong Kong.

The Neo Geo Pocket is considered to be an unsuccessful console. Lower than expected sales resulted in its discontinuation in 1999, and was immediately succeeded by the Neo Geo Pocket Color, a full color device allowing the system to compete more easily with the dominant Game Boy Color handheld, and which also saw a western release. Though the system enjoyed only a short life, there were some significant games released on the system such as Samurai Shodown, and King of Fighters R-1.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/ngp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19981128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/sega32x.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA 32X</name>
		<desc>SEGA 32X rom set with box art. 

History:
The 32X is an add-on for the Mega Drive/Genesis video game console. Codenamed "Project Mars", the 32X was designed to expand the power of the Genesis and serve as a transitional console into the 32-bit era until the release of the Sega Saturn. Independent of the Genesis, the 32X uses its own ROM cartridges and has its own library of games. The add-on was distributed under the name Super 32X in Japan, Genesis 32X in North America, Mega Drive 32X in the PAL region, and Mega 32X in Brazil.

Unveiled by Sega at June 1994's Consumer Electronics Show, the 32X was presented as a low-cost option for consumers looking to play 32-bit games. Developed in response to the Atari Jaguar and concerns that the Saturn would not make it to market by the end of 1994, the product was conceived as an entirely new console. At the suggestion of Sega of America executive Joe Miller and his team, the console was converted into an add-on to the existing Genesis and made more powerful. The final design contained two 32-bit central processing units and a 3D graphics processor. To bring the new add-on to market by its scheduled release date of November 1994, development of the new system and its games were rushed. The console failed to attract third-party video game developers and consumers because of the announcement of the Sega Saturn's simultaneous release in Japan. Sega's efforts to rush the 32X to market cut into available time for game development, resulting in a weak library of forty titles that could not fully use the add-on's hardware, including Genesis ports. By the end of 1994, the 32X had sold 665,000 units. After price reductions in 1995, it was discontinued in 1996 as Sega turned its focus to the Saturn.

The 32X is considered a commercial failure. Reception after the add-on's unveiling and launch was positive, highlighting the low price of the system and power expansion to the Genesis. Later reviews, both contemporary and retrospective, for the 32X have been mostly negative because of its shallow game library, poor market timing and the resulting market fragmentation for the Genesis.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sega32x.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941121T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/sfc.sh</path>
		<name>Super Famicom</name>
		<desc>Super Famicom.

History:
The Super Nintendo Entertainment System, and commonly shortened to Super Nintendo is a 16-bit home video game console developed by Nintendo that was released in 1990 in Japan and South Korea, 1991 in North America, 1992 in Europe and Australasia (Oceania), and 1993 in South America. In Japan, the system is called the Super Famicom, officially adopting the abbreviated name of its predecessor, the Famicom, or SFC for short. In South Korea, it is known as the Super Comboy and was distributed by Hyundai Electronics. Although each version is essentially the same, several forms of regional lockout prevent the different versions from being compatible with one another. It was released in Brazil on September 2, 1992, by Playtronic.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sfc.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19900000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/sgfx.sh</path>
		<name>Super Grafx</name>
		<desc>Super Grafx rom set with box art. 

History:
The PC Engine SuperGrafx, also shortened as the SuperGrafx or PC Engine SG, is a video game console by NEC Home Electronics, released exclusively in Japan. It is an upgraded version of the PC Engine, released two years prior. Like the PC Engine, the SuperGrafx was also imported and sold in France.

Originally announced as the PC Engine 2, the machine was purported to be a true 16-bit system with improved graphics and audio capabilities over the original PC Engine. Expected to be released in 1990, the SuperGrafx was rushed to market, debuting several months earlier in late 1989 with only modest improvements over the original PC Engine.

Only seven games were produced which took advantage of the improved SuperGrafx hardware, and two of those could be played on a regular PC Engine. However, the SuperGrafx is backwards compatible with all PC Engine software in both, HuCard and CD-ROM2 format, bringing the compatible software total up to nearly 700. The system was not widely adopted and is largely seen as a commercial failure.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sgfx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19891208T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/snes.sh</path>
		<name>Super Nintendo</name>
		<desc>Super Nintendo rom set with box art. 

History:
The SNES is Nintendo's second home console, following the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES). The console introduced advanced graphics and sound capabilities compared with other systems at the time. The development of a variety of enhancement chips integrated in game cartridges helped to keep it competitive in the marketplace.

The SNES was a global success, becoming the best-selling console of the 16-bit era despite its relatively late start and the fierce competition it faced in North America and Europe from Sega's Genesis/Mega Drive console. The SNES remained popular well into the 32-bit era, and continues to be popular among fans, collectors, retro gamers, and emulation enthusiasts, some of whom still make homebrew ROM images.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/snes.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19910823T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/tg16.sh</path>
		<name>TurboGrafx 16</name>
		<desc>TurboGrafx 16 rom set with box art. 

History:
The TurboGrafx-16 Entertainment SuperSystem, known in Japan and France as the PC Engine (Pi Shi Enjin), is a home video game console jointly developed by Hudson Soft and NEC Home Electronics, released in Japan on October 30, 1987 and in the United States on August 29, 1989. It also had a limited release in the United Kingdom and Spain in 1990, known as simply TurboGrafx and based on the American model, whilst the Japanese model was imported and distributed in France in 1989. It was the first console released in the 16-bit era, albeit still utilizing an 8-bit CPU. Originally intended to compete with the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES), it ended up competing with the Sega Genesis, and later on the Super Nintendo Entertainment System (SNES).

The TurboGrafx-16 has an 8-bit CPU, a 16-bit video color encoder, and a 16-bit video display controller. The GPUs are capable of displaying 482 colors simultaneously, out of 512. With dimensions of just 14 cm◊14 cm◊3.8 cm (5.5 in◊5.5 in◊1.5 in), the Japanese PC Engine is the smallest major home game console ever made. Games were stored on a HuCard cartridge, or in CD-ROM optical format with the TurboGrafx-CD add-on.

The TurboGrafx-16 failed to break into the North American market and sold poorly, which has been blamed on inferior marketing. However in Japan the PC Engine was very successful, where it gained strong third-party support and outsold the Famicom at its 1987 debut, eventually becoming the Super Famicom's main rival. Lots of revisions - at least 17 distinct models - were made, such as portable versions and a CD-ROM add-on. A short lived successor, PC Engine SuperGrafx, failed to break through and was quickly discontinued. The entire series was succeeded by the PC-FX in 1994, only released in Japan.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/tg16.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890829T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/vectrex.sh</path>
		<name>Vectrex</name>
		<desc>Vectrex rom set with box art. 

History:
The Vectrex is a vector display-based home video game console that was developed by Western Technologies/Smith Engineering.[1] It was licensed and distributed first by General Consumer Electronics (GCE), and then by Milton Bradley Company after its purchase of GCE. It was released in November 1982 at a retail price of $199 ($480 adjusted for inflation[2]); as Milton Bradley took over international marketing the price dropped to $150, then reduced again to $100 shortly before the video game crash of 1983 and finally retailed at $49 after the crash.[3] The Vectrex exited the console market in early 1984.

Unlike other non-portable video game consoles, which connected to televisions and rendered raster graphics, the Vectrex has an integrated vector monitor which displays vector graphics. The Vectrex is monochrome and uses plastic screen overlays to simulate color and various static graphics and decorations. At the time, many of the most popular arcade games used vector displays, and through a licensing deal with Cinematronics, GCE was able to produce high-quality versions of arcade games such as Space Wars and Armor Attack.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/Vectrex.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19821101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Western Technologies/Smith Engineering</developer>
		<publisher>General Consumer Electronics and Milton Bradley Company</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/videopac2.sh</path>
		<name>Magnavox Odyssey 2 / Videopac 2</name>
		<desc>Magnavox Odyssey 2 / Videopac 2 rom set. 

History:
The Magnavox Odyssey², also known as Philips Odyssey2 is a second generation home video game console released in 1978. It was sold in Europe as the Philips Videopac G7000, in Brazil as the Philips Odyssey and in Japan as Odyssey2. Odyssey2 was one of the major three home consoles prior to the 1983 video game market crash, along with Atari 2600 and IntelliVision.

In the early 1970s, Magnavox pioneered the home video game industry by successfully bringing the first home console to market, the Odyssey, which was quickly followed by a number of later models, each with a few technological improvements (see Magnavox Odyssey series). In 1978, Magnavox, now a subsidiary of North American Philips, decided to release an all-new successor, Odyssey2.

In 2009, the video game website IGN named the Odyssey2 the 21st greatest video game console, out of its list of 25
</desc>
		<image>./icons/videopac2.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20041128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Magnavox</developer>
		<publisher>Magnavox</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/virtualboy.sh</path>
		<name>Virtual Boy</name>
		<desc>Virtual Boy rom set with box art. 

History:
The Virtual Boy is a 32-bit table-top video game console developed and manufactured by Nintendo. Released in 1995, it was marketed as the first console capable of displaying stereoscopic 3D graphics. The player uses the console in a manner similar to a head-mounted display, placing their head against the eyepiece to see a red monochrome display. The games use a parallax effect to create the illusion of depth. Sales failed to meet targets, and by early 1996, Nintendo ceased distribution and game development, only ever releasing 22 games for the system.

Development of the Virtual Boy lasted four years, and began originally under the project name of VR32. Nintendo entered a licensing agreement to utilize a 3D LED eyepiece technology originally developed by U.S.-based company Reflection Technology. It also built a factory in China to be used exclusively for Virtual Boy manufacturing. Over the course of development, the console technology was down-scaled due to high costs and potential health concerns. Furthermore, an increasing amount of company resources were being re-allocated to Nintendo 64 development. Lead Nintendo game designer, Shigeru Miyamoto, had little involvement with the Virtual Boy software. The console was pushed to market in an unfinished state in 1995 to focus on Nintendo 64 development.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/VirtualBoy.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19950000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/wonderswan.sh</path>
		<name>WonderSwan</name>
		<desc>WonderSwan rom set with box art. 

History:
The WonderSwan is a handheld game console released in Japan by Bandai. It was developed by Gunpei Yokoi's company Koto Laboratory and Bandai, and was the last piece of hardware Yokoi developed before his death in 1997. Released in 1999 in the fifth generation of video game consoles, the WonderSwan and its two later models, the WonderSwan Color and SwanCrystal were officially supported until being discontinued by Bandai in 2003. During its lifespan, no variation of the WonderSwan was released outside of Japan.

Powered by a 16-bit central processing unit, the WonderSwan took advantage of a low price point and long battery life in comparison to its competition, Nintendo's Game Boy Color and SNK's Neo Geo Pocket Color. Later improvements took advantage of quality upgrades to the handheld's screen and added color. The WonderSwan is playable both vertically and horizontally, and features a unique library of games, including numerous first-party titles based on licensed anime properties, as well as significant third-party support from Square, Namco, and Taito.

Overall, the WonderSwan in all its variations combined to sell an estimated 3.5 million units and managed to obtain as much as 8% of the Japanese handheld video game console market before being marginalized by Nintendo's Game Boy Advance. Retrospective feedback praises the potential of the WonderSwan despite its low sales and its brief time holding its own against Nintendo in the marketplace.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/WonderSwan.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19990304T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bandai</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/wonderswancolor.sh</path>
		<name>WonderSwan Color</name>
		<desc>WonderSwan Color rom set with box art.

History:
A redesign of the WonderSwan Color, titled SwanCrystal, was released in Japan on July 12, 2002. Once again, Bandai held a poll on its website to determine casing colors and released the system in blue violet, wine red, crystal blue, and crystal black. Despite its low price and an improved LCD screen, the SwanCrystal was unable to compete, so Bandai announced the discontinuation of the WonderSwan line in 2003 due to low demand and backed out of producing video game hardware altogether. In all, the handheld sold 3.5 million units, of which 1.55 million were of the original WonderSwan and at least 1.1 million were of the WonderSwan Color.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/WonderSwanColor.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20021712T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bandai</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/vectrex.sh</path>
		<name>Vectrex</name>
		<desc>Vectrex rom set with box art. 

History:
The Vectrex is a vector display-based home video game console that was developed by Western Technologies/Smith Engineering.[1] It was licensed and distributed first by General Consumer Electronics (GCE), and then by Milton Bradley Company after its purchase of GCE. It was released in November 1982 at a retail price of $199 ($480 adjusted for inflation[2]); as Milton Bradley took over international marketing the price dropped to $150, then reduced again to $100 shortly before the video game crash of 1983 and finally retailed at $49 after the crash.[3] The Vectrex exited the console market in early 1984.

Unlike other non-portable video game consoles, which connected to televisions and rendered raster graphics, the Vectrex has an integrated vector monitor which displays vector graphics. The Vectrex is monochrome and uses plastic screen overlays to simulate color and various static graphics and decorations. At the time, many of the most popular arcade games used vector displays, and through a licensing deal with Cinematronics, GCE was able to produce high-quality versions of arcade games such as Space Wars and Armor Attack.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/Vectrex.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19821101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Western Technologies/Smith Engineering</developer>
		<publisher>General Consumer Electronics and Milton Bradley Company</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atari2600.sh</path>
		<name>atari 2600</name>
		<desc>Atari 2600 rom set. 

History:
The Atari 2600 (or Atari VCS before November 1982) is a home video game console by Atari, Inc. Released on September 11, 1977, it is credited with popularizing the use of microprocessor-based hardware and ROM cartridges containing game code, a format first used with the Fairchild Channel F video game console in 1976. This format contrasts with the older model of having non-microprocessor dedicated hardware, which could only play the games that were physically built into the unit.

For five years, from 1977 until late 1982, the system was officially sold as the Atari VCS, an abbreviation for Video Computer System. Following the release of the Atari 5200 in November 1982, the VCS was renamed to the "Atari 2600", after the unit's Atari part number, CX2600. The 2600 was typically bundled with two joystick controllers, a conjoined pair of paddle controllers, and a game cartridge: initially Combat,and later Pac-Man. 
</desc>
		<image>./icons/a2600.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19770911T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atari5200.sh</path>
		<name>atari 5200</name>
		<desc>Atari 5200 rom set. 

History:
The Atari 5200 SuperSystem, commonly known as the Atari 5200, is a home video game console that was introduced in 1982 by Atari Inc. as a higher-end complementary console for the popular Atari 2600. The 5200 was created to compete with the Intellivision, but wound up more directly competing with the ColecoVision shortly after its release.

The 5200's internal hardware is almost identical that of Atari's 8-bit computers, although software is not directly compatible between the two systems. The 5200's controllers have an analog joystick and a numeric keypad along with start, pause and reset buttons. The 360-degree non-centering joystick was touted as offering more control than the eight-way joystick controller offered with the Atari 2600. 
</desc>
		<image>./icons/a5200.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840521T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atari7800.sh</path>
		<name>atari 7800</name>
		<desc>Atari 7800 rom set. 

History:
The Atari 7800 ProSystem, or simply the Atari 7800, is a home video game console officially released by Atari Corporation in 1986. It is almost fully backward-compatible with the Atari 2600, the first console to have backward compatibility without the use of additional modules. It was considered affordable at a price of US$140.

The 7800 has significantly improved graphics hardware over the 2600, but uses the same audio chip. It also shipped with a different model of joystick than the 2600-standard CX40.

The 1986 launch is sometimes referred to as a "re-release" or "relaunch" because the Atari 7800 had originally been announced on May 21, 1984, to replace Atari Inc.'s Atari 5200, but a general release was shelved due to the sale of the company. 
</desc>
		<image>./icons/a7800.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atarijaguar.sh</path>
		<name>Atari Jaguar</name>
		<desc>Atari Jaguar rom set. 

History:
The Atari Jaguar is a home video game console that was developed by Atari Corporation. The console was the sixth and last programmable console to be developed under the Atari brand, originally released in North America in November 1993. Controversially, Atari marketed the Jaguar as being the first 64-bit video game console, while competing with the existing 16-bit consoles (Sega Genesis and Super Nintendo Entertainment System) and the 32-bit 3DO Interactive Multiplayer platform (which launched the same year).

Development on the Atari Jaguar started in the early 1990s, and was designed by Flare Technology, who were tasked by Atari to create two consoles; the Atari Panther, which would compete with the Genesis and the Super NES, and a successor, the Jaguar, which would surpass the capabilities of any other console on the market at the time. With development of the Jaguar running ahead of schedule, the Panther was cancelled, and the release of the Jaguar was pushed forward. It was originally released to test markets in New York City and San Francisco in November 1993, and to the general public in 1994, with Cybermorph as the pack-in launch game.

The console's multi-chip architecture made game development for the console difficult, and underwhelming sales further contributed to the console's lack of third party support. This, in addition to the lack of internal development at Atari, led to a limited games library, comprising only 67 licensed titles.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/aj.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19931123T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/atarilynx.sh</path>
		<name>Atari Lynx</name>
		<desc>Atari Lynx rom set. 

History:
The Atari Lynx is a 16-bit handheld game console that was released by Atari Corporation in September 1989 in North America, and in Europe and Japan in 1990. The Lynx holds the distinction of being the world's first handheld electronic game with a color LCD. The system is also notable for its forward-looking features, advanced graphics, and ambidextrous layout. The Lynx competed with the Game Boy (released just 2 months earlier), as well as the Game Gear and TurboExpress, both released the following year. It was discontinued in 1995.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/lynx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/coleco.sh</path>
		<name>ColecoVision</name>
		<desc>ColecoVision. 

History:
The ColecoVision is Coleco Industries' second-generation home video-game console which was released in August 1982. The ColecoVision offered a closer experience to more powerful arcade game systems compared to competitors such as the Atari 2600, along with the means to expand the system's basic hardware.

The initial catalog of twelve games included Nintendo's Donkey Kong as the pack-in cartridge, Sega's graphically impressive Zaxxon, and some lesser known arcade titles that found a larger audience on the console, such as Lady Bug, Cosmic Avenger, and Venture. Approximately 145 titles in total were published as ROM cartridges for the system between 1982 and 1984.

Coleco withdrew from the video game market in 1985, and ColecoVision was discontinued that same year.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/col.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820811T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Coleco Industries</developer>
		<publisher>Coleco Industries</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/fba.sh</path>
		<name>Final Burn Alpha</name>
		<desc>Final Burn Alpha rom set. 
There is a custom gamelist installed with this set
History:
Final Burn Alpha is a Multiple Arcade Emulator most popular for emulating Neo-Geo, Capcom, Konami, and Cave games.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/fba.png</image>
		<rating />
		<releasedate />
		<developer />
		<publisher />
		<genre />
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/fds.sh</path>
		<name>Famicom Disk System</name>
		<desc>Famicom Disk System rom set. 

History:
Famicom Disk System device is connected to the Famicom deck by plugging a special cartridge known as the RAM Adapter into the system's cartridge port, and attaching that cartridge's cable to the disk drive. The RAM adapter contains 32 kilobytes (KB) of RAM for temporary program storage, 8 KB of RAM for tile and sprite data storage, and an ASIC known as the 2C33. The ASIC acts as a disk controller for the floppy drive, and also includes additional sound hardware featuring a single-cycle wavetable-lookup synthesizer. Finally, embedded in the 2C33 is an 8KB BIOS ROM. The Disk Cards used are double-sided, with a total capacity of 112 KB per disk. Many games span both sides of a disk, requiring the user to switch sides at some point during gameplay. A few games use two full disks, totaling four sides. The Disk System is capable of running on six C-cell batteries or the supplied AC adapter. Batteries usually last five months with daily game play. The battery option is due to the likelihood of a standard set of AC plugs already being occupied by a Famicom and a television.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/fds.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860221T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20170627T214550</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gamegear.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA Game Gear</name>
		<desc>SEGA Master System rom set. 

History:
The Game Gear is an 8-bit handheld game console released by Sega on October 6, 1990 in Japan, 1991 in North America and Europe, and Australia in 1992. The Game Gear primarily competed with Nintendo's Game Boy, the Atari Lynx and NEC's TurboExpress. The handheld shares much of its hardware with the Master System and is able to play its own titles as well as those of the Master System, the latter being made possible by the use of an adapter. Containing a full-color backlit screen with a landscape format, Sega positioned the Game Gear as a technologically superior handheld to the Game Boy.

Though the Game Gear was rushed to market, its unique game library and price point gave it an edge over the Atari Lynx and TurboExpress. However, due to issues with its short battery life, lack of original titles, and weak support from Sega, the Game Gear was unable to surpass the Game Boy, selling 10.62 million units by March 1996. The Game Gear was succeeded by the Genesis Nomad in 1995 and discontinued in 1997. It was re-released as a budget system by Majesco Entertainment in 2000, under license by Sega.

Reception of the Game Gear was mixed, with praise for its full-color backlit screen and processing power for its time, criticisms over its large size and short battery life, and questions over the quality of its game library.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/gg.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901006T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gb.sh</path>
		<name>Game Boy</name>
		<desc>Game Boy rom set. 

History:
The Game Boy is Nintendo's second handheld system following the Game &amp; Watch series introduced in 1980 and it combined features from both the Nintendo Entertainment System and Game &amp; Watch.[10] It was either bought as a standalone unit or bundled with the puzzle game Tetris.[11]

During its early lifetime, the Game Boy mainly competed with Sega's Game Gear, Atari's Lynx, and NEC's TurboExpress. The Game Boy beat its rivals and became a tremendous success.[12] The Game Boy and its successor, the Game Boy Color,[8] have sold over 118 million units worldwide. Upon the Game Boy's release in the United States, it sold its entire shipment of one million units within a few weeks.[13] The Game Boy and Game Boy Color were discontinued in the early 2000s in favor of the subsequent Game Boy Advance, released in 2001.[14] It is currently the second best-selling hand-held console of all time, the Nintendo DS being the first.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/GameBoy.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890421T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gba1.sh</path>
		<name>Game Boy Advanced Part 1</name>
		<desc>Game Boy Advanced Part 1 rom set. 

History:
The Game Boy Advance is a 32-bit handheld video game console developed, manufactured and marketed by Nintendo as the successor to the Game Boy Color. It was released in Japan on March 21, 2001, in North America on June 11, 2001, in Australia and Europe on June 22, 2001, and in mainland China on June 8, 2004 (iQue Player). Nintendo's competitors in the handheld market at the time were the Neo Geo Pocket Color, WonderSwan, GP32, Tapwave Zodiac, and the N-Gage. Despite the competitors' best efforts, Nintendo maintained a majority market share with the Game Boy Advance.

As of June 30, 2010, the Game Boy Advance series has sold 81.51 million units worldwide.[4] Its successor, the Nintendo DS, was released in November 2004 and is also compatible with Game Boy Advance software.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NintendoGameBoyAdvance.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20010421T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gba2.sh</path>
		<name>Game Boy Advanced Part 2</name>
		<desc>Game Boy Advanced part 2 rom set. 

History:
The Game Boy Advance is a 32-bit handheld video game console developed, manufactured and marketed by Nintendo as the successor to the Game Boy Color. It was released in Japan on March 21, 2001, in North America on June 11, 2001, in Australia and Europe on June 22, 2001, and in mainland China on June 8, 2004 (iQue Player). Nintendo's competitors in the handheld market at the time were the Neo Geo Pocket Color, WonderSwan, GP32, Tapwave Zodiac, and the N-Gage. Despite the competitors' best efforts, Nintendo maintained a majority market share with the Game Boy Advance.

As of June 30, 2010, the Game Boy Advance series has sold 81.51 million units worldwide.[4] Its successor, the Nintendo DS, was released in November 2004 and is also compatible with Game Boy Advance software.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NintendoGameBoyAdvance.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20010421T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gba3.sh</path>
		<name>Game Boy Advanced Part 3</name>
		<desc>Game Boy Advanced part 3 rom set. 

History:
The Game Boy Advance is a 32-bit handheld video game console developed, manufactured and marketed by Nintendo as the successor to the Game Boy Color. It was released in Japan on March 21, 2001, in North America on June 11, 2001, in Australia and Europe on June 22, 2001, and in mainland China on June 8, 2004 (iQue Player). Nintendo's competitors in the handheld market at the time were the Neo Geo Pocket Color, WonderSwan, GP32, Tapwave Zodiac, and the N-Gage. Despite the competitors' best efforts, Nintendo maintained a majority market share with the Game Boy Advance.

As of June 30, 2010, the Game Boy Advance series has sold 81.51 million units worldwide.[4] Its successor, the Nintendo DS, was released in November 2004 and is also compatible with Game Boy Advance software.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NintendoGameBoyAdvance.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20010421T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/gbc.sh</path>
		<name>Game Boy Color</name>
		<desc>Game Boy Color. 

History:
The Game Boy Color is a handheld game console manufactured by Nintendo, which was released on October 21, 1998 in Japan[8] and was released in November of the same year in international markets. It is the successor of the Game Boy.

The Game Boy Color, as suggested by the name, features a color screen, but no backlight. It is slightly thicker and taller than the Game Boy Pocket, which is a redesigned Game Boy released in 1996. As with the original Game Boy, it has a custom 8-bit processor somewhat related to a Zilog Z80 central processing unit (CPU).[9] The original name – with its American English spelling of "color" – remained unchanged even in markets where "colour" was the accepted English spelling.

The Game Boy Color's primary competitors were the much more advanced Neo Geo Pocket by SNK and the WonderSwan by Bandai (both released in Japan only), though the Game Boy Color outsold these by a wide margin. The Game Boy and Game Boy Color combined have sold 118.69 million units worldwide.[1][2] It was discontinued in 2003, shortly after the release of the Game Boy Advance SP.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/GameBoyColor.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19881021T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/intellivision.sh</path>
		<name>Intellivision</name>
		<desc>Intellivision rom set. 

History:
The Intellivision is a home video game console released by Mattel Electronics in 1979. The name Intellivision is a portmanteau of "intelligent television". Development of the console began in 1977, the same year as the introduction of its main competitor, the Atari 2600. In 1984 Mattel sold the Intellivision business to a former Mattel Electronics executive and investors that would become INTV Corporation. Games development started in 1978 and continued until 1990 when the Intellivision was discontinued. From 1980 to 1983 over 3 million Intellivision units were sold.

In 2009, video game website IGN named the Intellivision the No. 14 greatest video game console of all time. It remained Mattel's only video game console until the release of the HyperScan in 2006.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/intellivision.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19790000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Mattel Electronics</developer>
		<publisher>Mattel Electronics</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/mastersystem.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA Master System</name>
		<desc>SEGA Master System rom set. 

History:
The Sega Master System is a third-generation home video game console that was manufactured by Sega. It was originally released in 1985 as the Sega Mark III in Japan. After being redesigned prior to its North American launch, the console was renamed Master System and released in 1986 in North America, 1987 in Europe, and 1989 in Brazil. The Master System was also released in Japan in 1987 with additional features over the overseas models. Both the Mark III and the original Master System models could play with both cartridges (or "Mega Cartridges", as they were officially called) and the credit card-sized Sega Cards, which retailed at lower prices than cartridges but had lower storage capacity; the Master System II and later models did not have the card slot. The Master System also featured accessories such as a light gun and 3D glasses which were designed to work with a range of specially coded games.

Succeeding the SG-1000, the Master System was released as a direct competitor to the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) in the third generation of video game consoles. The Master System was constructed with hardware superior to that of the NES, but failed to overturn Nintendo's significant market share advantage in Japan and North America. However, it attained significantly more success in Europe and Brazil. The hardware of the Master System also shared many similarities with Sega's handheld game console, the Sega Game Gear. Compared to its competition from Nintendo, the Master System's game library lacks a number of well-received titles due to Nintendo's licensing practices that restricted third-party developers from creating games for any system other than the NES. Sales of the console have been estimated between 10 and 13 million units, not including recent Brazil sales, compared to 62 million NES units sold. Reception to the system given in retrospect lends credit to the console's role in Sega's development of the Sega Genesis, as well as for having a number of well-received titles, particularly in PAL regions, but is generally critical of its small game library. As of 2015, the Master System is the longest-lived game console (30 years and continuing), due to its popularity in Brazil.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sms.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19851020T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/megadrive.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA MegaDrive/Genesis</name>
		<desc>SEGA MegaDrive/Genesis rom set. 

History:
The Sega Genesis, known as the Mega Drive in most regions outside of North America, is a 16-bit home video game console which was developed and sold by Sega Enterprises, Ltd. The Genesis was Sega's third console and the successor to the Master System. Sega first released the console as the Mega Drive in Japan in 1988, followed by a North American debut under the Genesis moniker in 1989. In 1990, the console was distributed as the Mega Drive by Virgin Mastertronic in Europe, by Ozisoft in Australasia, and by Tectoy in Brazil. In South Korea, the systems were distributed by Samsung and were known as the Super Gam*Boy, and later the Super Aladdin Boy.

Designed by an R&amp;D team supervised by Hideki Sato and Masami Ishikawa, the hardware was adapted from Sega's System 16 arcade board, centered on a Motorola 68000 processor as a primary CPU and a Zilog Z80 as a secondary processor. The system supports a library of more than 900 games created both by Sega and a wide array of third-party publishers and delivered on ROM-based cartridges. It can play Master System games when the separately sold Power Base Converter is inserted. The Genesis has benefited from several peripherals and network services, as well as multiple first-party and third-party variations of the console that focus on extending its functionality.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/megadrive.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19881029T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/megadrive-japan.sh</path>
		<name>Sega Megadrive Japan</name>
		<desc>Sega Megadrive Japan rom set. 

History:
Sega first released the console as the Mega Drive in Japan in 1988, followed by a North American debut under the Genesis moniker in 1989. In 1990, the console was distributed as the Mega Drive by Virgin Mastertronic in Europe, by Ozisoft in Australasia, and by Tectoy in Brazil. In South Korea, the systems were distributed by Samsung and were known as the Super Gam*Boy, and later the Super Aladdin Boy.

Designed by an R&amp;D team supervised by Hideki Sato and Masami Ishikawa, the hardware was adapted from Sega's System 16 arcade board, centered on a Motorola 68000 processor as a primary CPU and a Zilog Z80 as a secondary processor. The system supports a library of more than 900 games created both by Sega and a wide array of third-party publishers and delivered on ROM-based cartridges. It can play Master System games when the separately sold Power Base Converter is inserted. The Genesis has benefited from several peripherals and network services, as well as multiple first-party and third-party variations of the console that focus on extending its functionality.

In Japan, the Mega Drive did not fare well against its two main competitors, Nintendo's Super Famicom and NEC's PC Engine, but achieved considerable success in North America, Brazil and Europe. Contributing to its success were its library of arcade game ports, the popularity of the Genesis-exclusive Sonic the Hedgehog series, several popular sports game franchises, and aggressive youth marketing that positioned the system as the cool console for adolescents. The release of the Super Nintendo Entertainment System two years after the Genesis resulted in a fierce battle for market share in the United States and Europe that has often been termed as a "console war" by journalists and historians.[2][3] As this contest drew increasing attention to the video game industry among the general public, the Genesis and several of its highest-profile games attracted significant legal scrutiny on matters involving reverse engineering and video game violence. Controversy surrounding violent titles such as Night Trap and Mortal Kombat led Sega to create the Videogame Rating Council, a predecessor to the Entertainment Software Rating Board.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/megadrive_art_blur.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega Enterprises, Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Sega Enterprises, Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount>0</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20170628T162642</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/msx.sh</path>
		<name>MSX</name>
		<desc>MSX rom set, released in 1983. 

History:
MSX is the name of a standardized home computer architecture, first announced by Microsoft on June 16, 1983, and marketed by Kazuhiko Nishi, then Vice-president at Microsoft Japan and Director at ASCII Corporation. Microsoft conceived the project as an attempt to create unified standards among various hardware makers of the period.

They were popular mostly in Japan, and several other countries. It is difficult to estimate how many MSX computers were sold worldwide, but eventually 5 million MSX-based units were sold in Japan alone. Despite Microsoft's involvement, the MSX-based machines were seldom released in the United States.

Before the appearance and great success of Nintendo's Family Computer, MSX was the platform for which major Japanese game studios, such as Konami and Hudson Soft, produced video game titles. The Metal Gear series, for example, was originally written for MSX hardware.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/msx_art_blur.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830616T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Microsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Microsoft</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/msx2.sh</path>
		<name>MSX 2</name>
		<desc>MSX 2 rom set, released in 1985. 

History:
MSX is the name of a standardized home computer architecture, first announced by Microsoft on June 16, 1983, and marketed by Kazuhiko Nishi, then Vice-president at Microsoft Japan and Director at ASCII Corporation. Microsoft conceived the project as an attempt to create unified standards among various hardware makers of the period.

They were popular mostly in Japan, and several other countries. It is difficult to estimate how many MSX computers were sold worldwide, but eventually 5 million MSX-based units were sold in Japan alone. Despite Microsoft's involvement, the MSX-based machines were seldom released in the United States.

Before the appearance and great success of Nintendo's Family Computer, MSX was the platform for which major Japanese game studios, such as Konami and Hudson Soft, produced video game titles. The Metal Gear series, for example, was originally written for MSX hardware.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/msx_art_blur.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19850000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Microsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Microsoft</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/n64.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo 64</name>
		<desc>Nintendo 64 rom set, released in 1985. 

History:
The Nintendo 64, stylized as NINTENDO64 and abbreviated to N64, is Nintendo's third home video game console for the international market. Named for its 64-bit central processing unit, it was released in June 1996 in Japan, September 1996 in North America and Brazil, March 1997 in Europe and Australia, September 1997 in France. It was the last major home console to use the cartridge as its primary storage format until Nintendo's seventh console, the Nintendo Switch, released in 2017.[7] Though succeeded by Nintendo's MiniDVD-based GameCube in September 2001, the Nintendo 64 was sold until the system was retired in early 2002.

Codenamed "Project Reality", the Nintendo 64 design was mostly complete by mid-1995, but its launch was delayed until 1996, when Time named it Machine of the Year. It launched with three games: Super Mario 64 and Pilotwings 64, released worldwide, and Saikyō Habu Shōgi, released only in Japan. As part of the fifth generation of gaming, the system competed primarily with the Sony PlayStation and the Sega Saturn. The suggested retail price at its United States launch was US$199.99, and 32.93 million units were sold worldwide. The console was released in a range of colors and designs over its lifetime. In 2015, IGN named it the 9th greatest video game console of all time.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/n64.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19960000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/nds1.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo DS Part 1</name>
		<desc>Nintendo DS Part 1 rom set. 

History:
The Nintendo DS or simply, DS, is a 32-bit dual-screen handheld game console developed and released by Nintendo. The device went on sale in North America on November 21, 2004. The DS, short for "Developers' System" or "Dual Screen", introduced distinctive new features to handheld gaming: two LCD screens working in tandem (the bottom one featuring a touchscreen), a built-in microphone, and support for wireless connectivity. Both screens are encompassed within a clamshell design similar to the Game Boy Advance SP. The Nintendo DS also features the ability for multiple DS consoles to directly interact with each other over Wi-Fi within a short range without the need to connect to an existing wireless network. Alternatively, they could interact online using the now-closed Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection service. Its main competitor was Sony's PlayStation Portable as part of the seventh generation era. It was likened to the Nintendo 64 from the 1990s, which led to several N64 ports such as Super Mario 64 DS, Diddy Kong Racing DS, GoldenEye 007 and more.

Prior to its release, the Nintendo DS was marketed as an experimental, "third pillar" in Nintendo's console lineup, meant to complement the Game Boy Advance and GameCube. However, backward compatibility with Game Boy Advance titles and strong sales ultimately established it as the successor to the Game Boy series. On March 2, 2006, Nintendo launched the Nintendo DS Lite, a slimmer and lighter redesign of the original Nintendo DS with brighter screens. On November 1, 2008, Nintendo released the Nintendo DSi, another redesign with several hardware improvements and new features. All Nintendo DS models combined have sold 154.02 million units, making it the best selling handheld game console to date, and the second best selling video game console of all time behind Sony's PlayStation 2. The Nintendo DS line was succeeded by the Nintendo 3DS line in 2011.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NDS.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20041128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/nds2.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo DS Part 2</name>
		<desc>Nintendo DS Part 2 rom set. 

History:
The Nintendo DS or simply, DS, is a 32-bit dual-screen handheld game console developed and released by Nintendo. The device went on sale in North America on November 21, 2004. The DS, short for "Developers' System" or "Dual Screen", introduced distinctive new features to handheld gaming: two LCD screens working in tandem (the bottom one featuring a touchscreen), a built-in microphone, and support for wireless connectivity. Both screens are encompassed within a clamshell design similar to the Game Boy Advance SP. The Nintendo DS also features the ability for multiple DS consoles to directly interact with each other over Wi-Fi within a short range without the need to connect to an existing wireless network. Alternatively, they could interact online using the now-closed Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection service. Its main competitor was Sony's PlayStation Portable as part of the seventh generation era. It was likened to the Nintendo 64 from the 1990s, which led to several N64 ports such as Super Mario 64 DS, Diddy Kong Racing DS, GoldenEye 007 and more.

Prior to its release, the Nintendo DS was marketed as an experimental, "third pillar" in Nintendo's console lineup, meant to complement the Game Boy Advance and GameCube. However, backward compatibility with Game Boy Advance titles and strong sales ultimately established it as the successor to the Game Boy series. On March 2, 2006, Nintendo launched the Nintendo DS Lite, a slimmer and lighter redesign of the original Nintendo DS with brighter screens. On November 1, 2008, Nintendo released the Nintendo DSi, another redesign with several hardware improvements and new features. All Nintendo DS models combined have sold 154.02 million units, making it the best selling handheld game console to date, and the second best selling video game console of all time behind Sony's PlayStation 2. The Nintendo DS line was succeeded by the Nintendo 3DS line in 2011.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NDS.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20041128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/nds3.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo DS Part 3</name>
		<desc>Nintendo DS Part 3 rom set. 

History:
The Nintendo DS or simply, DS, is a 32-bit dual-screen handheld game console developed and released by Nintendo. The device went on sale in North America on November 21, 2004. The DS, short for "Developers' System" or "Dual Screen", introduced distinctive new features to handheld gaming: two LCD screens working in tandem (the bottom one featuring a touchscreen), a built-in microphone, and support for wireless connectivity. Both screens are encompassed within a clamshell design similar to the Game Boy Advance SP. The Nintendo DS also features the ability for multiple DS consoles to directly interact with each other over Wi-Fi within a short range without the need to connect to an existing wireless network. Alternatively, they could interact online using the now-closed Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection service. Its main competitor was Sony's PlayStation Portable as part of the seventh generation era. It was likened to the Nintendo 64 from the 1990s, which led to several N64 ports such as Super Mario 64 DS, Diddy Kong Racing DS, GoldenEye 007 and more.

Prior to its release, the Nintendo DS was marketed as an experimental, "third pillar" in Nintendo's console lineup, meant to complement the Game Boy Advance and GameCube. However, backward compatibility with Game Boy Advance titles and strong sales ultimately established it as the successor to the Game Boy series. On March 2, 2006, Nintendo launched the Nintendo DS Lite, a slimmer and lighter redesign of the original Nintendo DS with brighter screens. On November 1, 2008, Nintendo released the Nintendo DSi, another redesign with several hardware improvements and new features. All Nintendo DS models combined have sold 154.02 million units, making it the best selling handheld game console to date, and the second best selling video game console of all time behind Sony's PlayStation 2. The Nintendo DS line was succeeded by the Nintendo 3DS line in 2011.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NDS.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20041128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/nds4.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo DS Part 4</name>
		<desc>Nintendo DS Part 4 rom set. 

History:
The Nintendo DS or simply, DS, is a 32-bit dual-screen handheld game console developed and released by Nintendo. The device went on sale in North America on November 21, 2004. The DS, short for "Developers' System" or "Dual Screen", introduced distinctive new features to handheld gaming: two LCD screens working in tandem (the bottom one featuring a touchscreen), a built-in microphone, and support for wireless connectivity. Both screens are encompassed within a clamshell design similar to the Game Boy Advance SP. The Nintendo DS also features the ability for multiple DS consoles to directly interact with each other over Wi-Fi within a short range without the need to connect to an existing wireless network. Alternatively, they could interact online using the now-closed Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection service. Its main competitor was Sony's PlayStation Portable as part of the seventh generation era. It was likened to the Nintendo 64 from the 1990s, which led to several N64 ports such as Super Mario 64 DS, Diddy Kong Racing DS, GoldenEye 007 and more.

Prior to its release, the Nintendo DS was marketed as an experimental, "third pillar" in Nintendo's console lineup, meant to complement the Game Boy Advance and GameCube. However, backward compatibility with Game Boy Advance titles and strong sales ultimately established it as the successor to the Game Boy series. On March 2, 2006, Nintendo launched the Nintendo DS Lite, a slimmer and lighter redesign of the original Nintendo DS with brighter screens. On November 1, 2008, Nintendo released the Nintendo DSi, another redesign with several hardware improvements and new features. All Nintendo DS models combined have sold 154.02 million units, making it the best selling handheld game console to date, and the second best selling video game console of all time behind Sony's PlayStation 2. The Nintendo DS line was succeeded by the Nintendo 3DS line in 2011.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NDS.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20041128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/nds5.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo DS Part 5</name>
		<desc>Nintendo DS Part 5 rom set. 

History:
The Nintendo DS or simply, DS, is a 32-bit dual-screen handheld game console developed and released by Nintendo. The device went on sale in North America on November 21, 2004. The DS, short for "Developers' System" or "Dual Screen", introduced distinctive new features to handheld gaming: two LCD screens working in tandem (the bottom one featuring a touchscreen), a built-in microphone, and support for wireless connectivity. Both screens are encompassed within a clamshell design similar to the Game Boy Advance SP. The Nintendo DS also features the ability for multiple DS consoles to directly interact with each other over Wi-Fi within a short range without the need to connect to an existing wireless network. Alternatively, they could interact online using the now-closed Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection service. Its main competitor was Sony's PlayStation Portable as part of the seventh generation era. It was likened to the Nintendo 64 from the 1990s, which led to several N64 ports such as Super Mario 64 DS, Diddy Kong Racing DS, GoldenEye 007 and more.

Prior to its release, the Nintendo DS was marketed as an experimental, "third pillar" in Nintendo's console lineup, meant to complement the Game Boy Advance and GameCube. However, backward compatibility with Game Boy Advance titles and strong sales ultimately established it as the successor to the Game Boy series. On March 2, 2006, Nintendo launched the Nintendo DS Lite, a slimmer and lighter redesign of the original Nintendo DS with brighter screens. On November 1, 2008, Nintendo released the Nintendo DSi, another redesign with several hardware improvements and new features. All Nintendo DS models combined have sold 154.02 million units, making it the best selling handheld game console to date, and the second best selling video game console of all time behind Sony's PlayStation 2. The Nintendo DS line was succeeded by the Nintendo 3DS line in 2011.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/NDS.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20041128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/neogeo.sh</path>
		<name>Neo Geo</name>
		<desc>Neo Geo. 

History:
Neo Geo, is a family of video game hardware developed by SNK. On the market from 1990 to 2004, the brand originated with the release of an arcade system, the Neo Geo MVS and its home console counterpart, the Neo Geo AES. Both the arcade system and console were powerful for the time and the AES allows for perfect compatibility of games released for the MVS. However, the high price point for both the AES console and its games prevented it from directly competing with its contemporaries, the Sega Mega Drive (Genesis), Super NES (Super Famicom), and Turbo-Grafx 16 (PC Engine).However the MVS arcade became very successful in stores in Japan and North America.

Years later, SNK would release the Neo Geo CD, a more cost effective console with games released on compact discs. The console was met with limited success, due in part to its slow CD-ROM drive. In an attempt to compete with increasingly popular 3D games, SNK released the Hyper Neo Geo 64 arcade system in 1997 as the successor to its aging MVS. The system did not fare well and only a few games were released for it. A planned home console based on the hardware was never released. SNK later extended the brand by releasing two handheld consoles, the Neo Geo Pocket, and later Neo Geo Pocket Color, which briefly competed with Nintendo's Game Boy. Soon after their release, SNK encountered various legal and financial issues - however the original Neo Geo MVS and AES continued getting new games under new ownership until officially being discontinued in 2004, ending the brand.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/neogeo.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19900000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/nes.sh</path>
		<name>Nintendo Entertainment System</name>
		<desc>NES rom set. 

History:
The Nintendo Entertainment System (commonly abbreviated as NES) is an 8-bit home video game console that was developed and manufactured by Nintendo.

The best-selling gaming console of its time, the NES helped revitalize the US video game industry following the video game crash of 1983. With the NES, Nintendo introduced a now-standard business model of licensing third-party developers, authorizing them to produce and distribute titles for Nintendo's platform.

It was initially released in Japan as the Family Computer (Hepburn: Famiri Konpyuta) (also known by the portmanteau abbreviation Famicom (Famikon) and abbreviated as FC) on July 15, 1983, and was later released in North America during 1985, in Europe during 1986, and Australia in 1987. In South Korea, it was known as the Hyundai Comboy (Hyeondae Keomboi) and was distributed by SK Hynix which then was known as Hyundai Electronics. It was succeeded by the Super Nintendo Entertainment System.

In 2009, the Nintendo Entertainment System was named the single greatest video game console in history by IGN, in a list of 25. It was judged the second greatest console behind the Sega Dreamcast in PC Magazine's "Top 10 Video Game Consoles of All Time".
</desc>
		<image>./icons/nes.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19851018T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/ngp.sh</path>
		<name>Neo Geo Pocket</name>
		<desc>Neo Geo Pocket rom set. 

History:
The Neo Geo Pocket is a monochrome handheld game console released by SNK. It was the company's first handheld system and is part of the Neo Geo family. It debuted in Japan in late 1998 but never saw a western release, being exclusive to Japan and smaller Asian markets such as Hong Kong.

The Neo Geo Pocket is considered to be an unsuccessful console. Lower than expected sales resulted in its discontinuation in 1999, and was immediately succeeded by the Neo Geo Pocket Color, a full color device allowing the system to compete more easily with the dominant Game Boy Color handheld, and which also saw a western release. Though the system enjoyed only a short life, there were some significant games released on the system such as Samurai Shodown, and King of Fighters R-1.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/ngp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19981128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/ngpc.sh</path>
		<name>Neo Geo Pocket Color</name>
		<desc>Neo Geo Pocket Color rom set. 

History:
TThe Neo Geo Pocket Color (also stylized as NEOGEOPOCKET COLOR, often abbreviated NGPC), is a 16-bit color handheld video game console manufactured by SNK. It is a successor to SNK's monochrome Neo Geo Pocket handheld which debuted in 1998 in Japan, with the Color being fully backward compatible. The Neo Geo Pocket Color was released on March 16, 1999 in Japan, August 6, 1999 in North America, and on October 1, 1999 in Europe, entering markets all dominated by Nintendo.

After a good sales start in both the U.S. and Japan with 14 launch titles (a record at the time) subsequent low retail support in the U.S.,lack of communication with third-party developers by SNK's American management, the craze about Nintendo's PokÈmon franchise, anticipation of the 32-bit Game Boy Advance, as well as strong competition from Bandai's WonderSwan in Japan, led to a sales decline in both regions
</desc>
		<image>./icons/ngp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19990806T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/pspminis1.sh</path>
		<name>PSP Mini part 1</name>
		<desc>PSP Mini part 1 rom set. 

History:
The PlayStation Portable (PSP) is a handheld game console developed by Sony Development of the handheld was announced during E3 2003, and it was unveiled on May 11, 2004, at a Sony press conference before E3 2004. The system was released in Japan on December 12, 2004, in North America on March 24, 2005, and in the PAL region on September 1, 2005. It primarily competed with the Nintendo DS, as part of the seventh generation of video games consoles.

The PlayStation Portable became the most powerful portable system when launched, just after the Nintendo DS in 2004. It was the first real competitor to Nintendo's handheld domination, where many challengers, such as SNK's Neo Geo Pocket and Nokia's N-Gage, failed. Its GPU encompassed high-end graphics on a handheld, while its 4.3 inch viewing screen. and multi-media capabilities,. such as its video player and TV tuner, made the PlayStation Portable a major mobile entertainment device at the time.. It also features connectivity with the PlayStation 3, other PSPs and the Internet. It is the only handheld console to use an optical disc format, Universal Media Disc (UMD), as its primary storage medium.

The original PSP model (PSP-1000) was replaced by a slimmer model with design changes (PSP-2000/"Slim &amp; Lite") in 2007. Another remodeling followed in 2008, PSP-3000, which included a new screen and an inbuilt microphone. A complete redesign, PSP Go, came in 2009, followed by a budget model, PSP-E1000, in 2011. The PSP line was succeeded by the PlayStation Vita, released in December 2011 in Japan, and in February 2012 worldwide. The PlayStation Vita features backward compatibility with many PlayStation Portable games digitally released on the PlayStation Network, via PlayStation Store. Shipments of the PlayStation Portable ended throughout 2014 worldwide, having sold 80 million units in its 10-year lifetime
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20040511T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>PSN Store</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/pspminis2.sh</path>
		<name>PSP Mini part 2</name>
		<desc>PSP Mini part 2 rom set. 

History:
The PlayStation Portable (PSP) is a handheld game console developed by Sony Development of the handheld was announced during E3 2003, and it was unveiled on May 11, 2004, at a Sony press conference before E3 2004. The system was released in Japan on December 12, 2004, in North America on March 24, 2005, and in the PAL region on September 1, 2005. It primarily competed with the Nintendo DS, as part of the seventh generation of video games consoles.

The PlayStation Portable became the most powerful portable system when launched, just after the Nintendo DS in 2004. It was the first real competitor to Nintendo's handheld domination, where many challengers, such as SNK's Neo Geo Pocket and Nokia's N-Gage, failed. Its GPU encompassed high-end graphics on a handheld, while its 4.3 inch viewing screen. and multi-media capabilities,. such as its video player and TV tuner, made the PlayStation Portable a major mobile entertainment device at the time.. It also features connectivity with the PlayStation 3, other PSPs and the Internet. It is the only handheld console to use an optical disc format, Universal Media Disc (UMD), as its primary storage medium.

The original PSP model (PSP-1000) was replaced by a slimmer model with design changes (PSP-2000/"Slim &amp; Lite") in 2007. Another remodeling followed in 2008, PSP-3000, which included a new screen and an inbuilt microphone. A complete redesign, PSP Go, came in 2009, followed by a budget model, PSP-E1000, in 2011. The PSP line was succeeded by the PlayStation Vita, released in December 2011 in Japan, and in February 2012 worldwide. The PlayStation Vita features backward compatibility with many PlayStation Portable games digitally released on the PlayStation Network, via PlayStation Store. Shipments of the PlayStation Portable ended throughout 2014 worldwide, having sold 80 million units in its 10-year lifetime
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20040511T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>PSN Store</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/pspminis3.sh</path>
		<name>PSP Mini part 3</name>
		<desc>PSP Mini part 3 rom set. 

History:
The PlayStation Portable (PSP) is a handheld game console developed by Sony Development of the handheld was announced during E3 2003, and it was unveiled on May 11, 2004, at a Sony press conference before E3 2004. The system was released in Japan on December 12, 2004, in North America on March 24, 2005, and in the PAL region on September 1, 2005. It primarily competed with the Nintendo DS, as part of the seventh generation of video games consoles.

The PlayStation Portable became the most powerful portable system when launched, just after the Nintendo DS in 2004. It was the first real competitor to Nintendo's handheld domination, where many challengers, such as SNK's Neo Geo Pocket and Nokia's N-Gage, failed. Its GPU encompassed high-end graphics on a handheld, while its 4.3 inch viewing screen. and multi-media capabilities,. such as its video player and TV tuner, made the PlayStation Portable a major mobile entertainment device at the time.. It also features connectivity with the PlayStation 3, other PSPs and the Internet. It is the only handheld console to use an optical disc format, Universal Media Disc (UMD), as its primary storage medium.

The original PSP model (PSP-1000) was replaced by a slimmer model with design changes (PSP-2000/"Slim &amp; Lite") in 2007. Another remodeling followed in 2008, PSP-3000, which included a new screen and an inbuilt microphone. A complete redesign, PSP Go, came in 2009, followed by a budget model, PSP-E1000, in 2011. The PSP line was succeeded by the PlayStation Vita, released in December 2011 in Japan, and in February 2012 worldwide. The PlayStation Vita features backward compatibility with many PlayStation Portable games digitally released on the PlayStation Network, via PlayStation Store. Shipments of the PlayStation Portable ended throughout 2014 worldwide, having sold 80 million units in its 10-year lifetime
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20040511T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>PSN Store</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/pspminis4.sh</path>
		<name>PSP Mini part 4</name>
		<desc>PSP Mini part 4 rom set. 

History:
The PlayStation Portable (PSP) is a handheld game console developed by Sony Development of the handheld was announced during E3 2003, and it was unveiled on May 11, 2004, at a Sony press conference before E3 2004. The system was released in Japan on December 12, 2004, in North America on March 24, 2005, and in the PAL region on September 1, 2005. It primarily competed with the Nintendo DS, as part of the seventh generation of video games consoles.

The PlayStation Portable became the most powerful portable system when launched, just after the Nintendo DS in 2004. It was the first real competitor to Nintendo's handheld domination, where many challengers, such as SNK's Neo Geo Pocket and Nokia's N-Gage, failed. Its GPU encompassed high-end graphics on a handheld, while its 4.3 inch viewing screen. and multi-media capabilities,. such as its video player and TV tuner, made the PlayStation Portable a major mobile entertainment device at the time.. It also features connectivity with the PlayStation 3, other PSPs and the Internet. It is the only handheld console to use an optical disc format, Universal Media Disc (UMD), as its primary storage medium.

The original PSP model (PSP-1000) was replaced by a slimmer model with design changes (PSP-2000/"Slim &amp; Lite") in 2007. Another remodeling followed in 2008, PSP-3000, which included a new screen and an inbuilt microphone. A complete redesign, PSP Go, came in 2009, followed by a budget model, PSP-E1000, in 2011. The PSP line was succeeded by the PlayStation Vita, released in December 2011 in Japan, and in February 2012 worldwide. The PlayStation Vita features backward compatibility with many PlayStation Portable games digitally released on the PlayStation Network, via PlayStation Store. Shipments of the PlayStation Portable ended throughout 2014 worldwide, having sold 80 million units in its 10-year lifetime
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psp.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20040511T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>PSN Store</publisher>
		<genre>portable gaming system</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20170627T214550</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/psx1.sh</path>
		<name>PlayStation 56 Game set part 1</name>
		<desc>PlayStation 56 Game set part 1 rom set. 

History:
PlayStation is a gaming brand that consists of four home video game consoles, as well as a media center, an online service, a line of controllers, two handhelds and a phone, as well as multiple magazines. It is created and owned by Sony Interactive Entertainment since December 3, 1994, with the launch of the original PlayStation in Japan.[1]

The original console in the series was the first video game console to ship 100 million units, 9 years and 6 months after its initial launch.[2] Its successor, the PlayStation 2, was released in 2000. The PlayStation 2 is the best-selling home console to date, having reached over 155 million units sold as of December 28, 2012.[3] Sony's next console, the PlayStation 3, was released in 2006 and has sold over 80 million consoles worldwide as of November 2013.[4] Sony's latest console, the PlayStation 4, was released in 2013, selling 1 million consoles in its first 24 hours on sale, becoming the fastest selling console in history.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/psx2.sh</path>
		<name>PlayStation 56 Game set part 2</name>
		<desc>PlayStation 56 Game set part 2 rom set. 

History:
PlayStation is a gaming brand that consists of four home video game consoles, as well as a media center, an online service, a line of controllers, two handhelds and a phone, as well as multiple magazines. It is created and owned by Sony Interactive Entertainment since December 3, 1994, with the launch of the original PlayStation in Japan.[1]

The original console in the series was the first video game console to ship 100 million units, 9 years and 6 months after its initial launch.[2] Its successor, the PlayStation 2, was released in 2000. The PlayStation 2 is the best-selling home console to date, having reached over 155 million units sold as of December 28, 2012.[3] Sony's next console, the PlayStation 3, was released in 2006 and has sold over 80 million consoles worldwide as of November 2013.[4] Sony's latest console, the PlayStation 4, was released in 2013, selling 1 million consoles in its first 24 hours on sale, becoming the fastest selling console in history.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount>0</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20170628T162642</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/psx3.sh</path>
		<name>PlayStation 56 Game set part 3</name>
		<desc>PlayStation 56 Game set part 3 rom set. 

History:
PlayStation is a gaming brand that consists of four home video game consoles, as well as a media center, an online service, a line of controllers, two handhelds and a phone, as well as multiple magazines. It is created and owned by Sony Interactive Entertainment since December 3, 1994, with the launch of the original PlayStation in Japan.[1]

The original console in the series was the first video game console to ship 100 million units, 9 years and 6 months after its initial launch.[2] Its successor, the PlayStation 2, was released in 2000. The PlayStation 2 is the best-selling home console to date, having reached over 155 million units sold as of December 28, 2012.[3] Sony's next console, the PlayStation 3, was released in 2006 and has sold over 80 million consoles worldwide as of November 2013.[4] Sony's latest console, the PlayStation 4, was released in 2013, selling 1 million consoles in its first 24 hours on sale, becoming the fastest selling console in history.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/psx4.sh</path>
		<name>PlayStation 56 Game set part 4</name>
		<desc>PlayStation 56 Game set part 4 rom set. 

History:
PlayStation is a gaming brand that consists of four home video game consoles, as well as a media center, an online service, a line of controllers, two handhelds and a phone, as well as multiple magazines. It is created and owned by Sony Interactive Entertainment since December 3, 1994, with the launch of the original PlayStation in Japan.[1]

The original console in the series was the first video game console to ship 100 million units, 9 years and 6 months after its initial launch.[2] Its successor, the PlayStation 2, was released in 2000. The PlayStation 2 is the best-selling home console to date, having reached over 155 million units sold as of December 28, 2012.[3] Sony's next console, the PlayStation 3, was released in 2006 and has sold over 80 million consoles worldwide as of November 2013.[4] Sony's latest console, the PlayStation 4, was released in 2013, selling 1 million consoles in its first 24 hours on sale, becoming the fastest selling console in history.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/psx5.sh</path>
		<name>PlayStation 56 Game set part 5</name>
		<desc>PlayStation 56 Game set part 5 rom set. 

History:
PlayStation is a gaming brand that consists of four home video game consoles, as well as a media center, an online service, a line of controllers, two handhelds and a phone, as well as multiple magazines. It is created and owned by Sony Interactive Entertainment since December 3, 1994, with the launch of the original PlayStation in Japan.[1]

The original console in the series was the first video game console to ship 100 million units, 9 years and 6 months after its initial launch.[2] Its successor, the PlayStation 2, was released in 2000. The PlayStation 2 is the best-selling home console to date, having reached over 155 million units sold as of December 28, 2012.[3] Sony's next console, the PlayStation 3, was released in 2006 and has sold over 80 million consoles worldwide as of November 2013.[4] Sony's latest console, the PlayStation 4, was released in 2013, selling 1 million consoles in its first 24 hours on sale, becoming the fastest selling console in history.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/psx6.sh</path>
		<name>PlayStation 56 Game set part 6</name>
		<desc>PlayStation 56 Game set part 6 rom set. 

History:
PlayStation is a gaming brand that consists of four home video game consoles, as well as a media center, an online service, a line of controllers, two handhelds and a phone, as well as multiple magazines. It is created and owned by Sony Interactive Entertainment since December 3, 1994, with the launch of the original PlayStation in Japan.[1]

The original console in the series was the first video game console to ship 100 million units, 9 years and 6 months after its initial launch.[2] Its successor, the PlayStation 2, was released in 2000. The PlayStation 2 is the best-selling home console to date, having reached over 155 million units sold as of December 28, 2012.[3] Sony's next console, the PlayStation 3, was released in 2006 and has sold over 80 million consoles worldwide as of November 2013.[4] Sony's latest console, the PlayStation 4, was released in 2013, selling 1 million consoles in its first 24 hours on sale, becoming the fastest selling console in history.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/psx7.sh</path>
		<name>PlayStation 56 Game set part 7</name>
		<desc>PlayStation 56 Game set part 7 rom set. 

History:
PlayStation is a gaming brand that consists of four home video game consoles, as well as a media center, an online service, a line of controllers, two handhelds and a phone, as well as multiple magazines. It is created and owned by Sony Interactive Entertainment since December 3, 1994, with the launch of the original PlayStation in Japan.[1]

The original console in the series was the first video game console to ship 100 million units, 9 years and 6 months after its initial launch.[2] Its successor, the PlayStation 2, was released in 2000. The PlayStation 2 is the best-selling home console to date, having reached over 155 million units sold as of December 28, 2012.[3] Sony's next console, the PlayStation 3, was released in 2006 and has sold over 80 million consoles worldwide as of November 2013.[4] Sony's latest console, the PlayStation 4, was released in 2013, selling 1 million consoles in its first 24 hours on sale, becoming the fastest selling console in history.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/psx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/sega32x.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA 32X</name>
		<desc>SEGA 32X rom set. 

History:
The 32X is an add-on for the Mega Drive/Genesis video game console. Codenamed "Project Mars", the 32X was designed to expand the power of the Genesis and serve as a transitional console into the 32-bit era until the release of the Sega Saturn. Independent of the Genesis, the 32X uses its own ROM cartridges and has its own library of games. The add-on was distributed under the name Super 32X in Japan, Genesis 32X in North America, Mega Drive 32X in the PAL region, and Mega 32X in Brazil.

Unveiled by Sega at June 1994's Consumer Electronics Show, the 32X was presented as a low-cost option for consumers looking to play 32-bit games. Developed in response to the Atari Jaguar and concerns that the Saturn would not make it to market by the end of 1994, the product was conceived as an entirely new console. At the suggestion of Sega of America executive Joe Miller and his team, the console was converted into an add-on to the existing Genesis and made more powerful. The final design contained two 32-bit central processing units and a 3D graphics processor. To bring the new add-on to market by its scheduled release date of November 1994, development of the new system and its games were rushed. The console failed to attract third-party video game developers and consumers because of the announcement of the Sega Saturn's simultaneous release in Japan. Sega's efforts to rush the 32X to market cut into available time for game development, resulting in a weak library of forty titles that could not fully use the add-on's hardware, including Genesis ports. By the end of 1994, the 32X had sold 665,000 units. After price reductions in 1995, it was discontinued in 1996 as Sega turned its focus to the Saturn.

The 32X is considered a commercial failure. Reception after the add-on's unveiling and launch was positive, highlighting the low price of the system and power expansion to the Genesis. Later reviews, both contemporary and retrospective, for the 32X have been mostly negative because of its shallow game library, poor market timing and the resulting market fragmentation for the Genesis.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sega32x.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19941121T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/segacd1.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA CD part D-F</name>
		<desc>SEGA CD part D-F rom set. 

History:
The Sega CD, released as the Mega-CD in most regions outside North America, is a CD-ROM accessory for the Sega Genesis video game console designed and produced by Sega as part of the fourth generation of video game consoles. The add-on was released on December 12, 1991 in Japan, October 15, 1992 in North America, and 1993 in Europe. The Sega CD lets the user play CD-based games and adds extra hardware functionality, such as a faster central processing unit and graphic enhancements. It can also play audio CDs and CD+G discs.

Seeking to create an add-on device for the Genesis, Sega developed the unit to read compact discs as its storage medium. The main benefit of CD technology was greater storage capacity, which allowed for games to be nearly 320 times larger than their Genesis cartridge counterparts. This benefit manifested in the form of full motion video (FMV) games like the controversial Night Trap, which became a focus of the 1993 Congressional hearings on issues of video game violence and ratings. Sega Enterprises in Japan partnered with JVC to design the add-on and refused to consult with Sega of America until the project was completed. Sega of America assembled parts from various "dummy" units to obtain a working prototype. While the add-on became known for several well-received games such as Sonic the Hedgehog CD and Lunar: Eternal Blue, its game library contained a large number of Genesis ports and FMV titles. The Sega CD was redesigned a number of times, including once by Sega and several times by licensed third-party developers.

2.24 million Sega CD units were sold by March 1996, after which the system was officially discontinued as Sega shifted its focus to the Sega Saturn. Retrospective reception to the add-on is mixed, praising the Sega CD for its individual offerings and additions to the Genesis' functions, but offering criticism to the game library for its depth issues, the high price of the unit, and how the add-on was supported by Sega.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/segacd.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901015T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/segacd2.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA CD part H-M</name>
		<desc>SEGA CD part H-M rom set. 

History:
The Sega CD, released as the Mega-CD in most regions outside North America, is a CD-ROM accessory for the Sega Genesis video game console designed and produced by Sega as part of the fourth generation of video game consoles. The add-on was released on December 12, 1991 in Japan, October 15, 1992 in North America, and 1993 in Europe. The Sega CD lets the user play CD-based games and adds extra hardware functionality, such as a faster central processing unit and graphic enhancements. It can also play audio CDs and CD+G discs.

Seeking to create an add-on device for the Genesis, Sega developed the unit to read compact discs as its storage medium. The main benefit of CD technology was greater storage capacity, which allowed for games to be nearly 320 times larger than their Genesis cartridge counterparts. This benefit manifested in the form of full motion video (FMV) games like the controversial Night Trap, which became a focus of the 1993 Congressional hearings on issues of video game violence and ratings. Sega Enterprises in Japan partnered with JVC to design the add-on and refused to consult with Sega of America until the project was completed. Sega of America assembled parts from various "dummy" units to obtain a working prototype. While the add-on became known for several well-received games such as Sonic the Hedgehog CD and Lunar: Eternal Blue, its game library contained a large number of Genesis ports and FMV titles. The Sega CD was redesigned a number of times, including once by Sega and several times by licensed third-party developers.

2.24 million Sega CD units were sold by March 1996, after which the system was officially discontinued as Sega shifted its focus to the Sega Saturn. Retrospective reception to the add-on is mixed, praising the Sega CD for its individual offerings and additions to the Genesis' functions, but offering criticism to the game library for its depth issues, the high price of the unit, and how the add-on was supported by Sega.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/segacd.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901015T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/segacd3.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA CD part N-R</name>
		<desc>SEGA CD part N-R rom set. 

History:
The Sega CD, released as the Mega-CD in most regions outside North America, is a CD-ROM accessory for the Sega Genesis video game console designed and produced by Sega as part of the fourth generation of video game consoles. The add-on was released on December 12, 1991 in Japan, October 15, 1992 in North America, and 1993 in Europe. The Sega CD lets the user play CD-based games and adds extra hardware functionality, such as a faster central processing unit and graphic enhancements. It can also play audio CDs and CD+G discs.

Seeking to create an add-on device for the Genesis, Sega developed the unit to read compact discs as its storage medium. The main benefit of CD technology was greater storage capacity, which allowed for games to be nearly 320 times larger than their Genesis cartridge counterparts. This benefit manifested in the form of full motion video (FMV) games like the controversial Night Trap, which became a focus of the 1993 Congressional hearings on issues of video game violence and ratings. Sega Enterprises in Japan partnered with JVC to design the add-on and refused to consult with Sega of America until the project was completed. Sega of America assembled parts from various "dummy" units to obtain a working prototype. While the add-on became known for several well-received games such as Sonic the Hedgehog CD and Lunar: Eternal Blue, its game library contained a large number of Genesis ports and FMV titles. The Sega CD was redesigned a number of times, including once by Sega and several times by licensed third-party developers.

2.24 million Sega CD units were sold by March 1996, after which the system was officially discontinued as Sega shifted its focus to the Sega Saturn. Retrospective reception to the add-on is mixed, praising the Sega CD for its individual offerings and additions to the Genesis' functions, but offering criticism to the game library for its depth issues, the high price of the unit, and how the add-on was supported by Sega.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/segacd.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901015T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/segacd4.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA CD part S-Z</name>
		<desc>SEGA CD part S-Z rom set. 

History:
The Sega CD, released as the Mega-CD in most regions outside North America, is a CD-ROM accessory for the Sega Genesis video game console designed and produced by Sega as part of the fourth generation of video game consoles. The add-on was released on December 12, 1991 in Japan, October 15, 1992 in North America, and 1993 in Europe. The Sega CD lets the user play CD-based games and adds extra hardware functionality, such as a faster central processing unit and graphic enhancements. It can also play audio CDs and CD+G discs.

Seeking to create an add-on device for the Genesis, Sega developed the unit to read compact discs as its storage medium. The main benefit of CD technology was greater storage capacity, which allowed for games to be nearly 320 times larger than their Genesis cartridge counterparts. This benefit manifested in the form of full motion video (FMV) games like the controversial Night Trap, which became a focus of the 1993 Congressional hearings on issues of video game violence and ratings. Sega Enterprises in Japan partnered with JVC to design the add-on and refused to consult with Sega of America until the project was completed. Sega of America assembled parts from various "dummy" units to obtain a working prototype. While the add-on became known for several well-received games such as Sonic the Hedgehog CD and Lunar: Eternal Blue, its game library contained a large number of Genesis ports and FMV titles. The Sega CD was redesigned a number of times, including once by Sega and several times by licensed third-party developers.

2.24 million Sega CD units were sold by March 1996, after which the system was officially discontinued as Sega shifted its focus to the Sega Saturn. Retrospective reception to the add-on is mixed, praising the Sega CD for its individual offerings and additions to the Genesis' functions, but offering criticism to the game library for its depth issues, the high price of the unit, and how the add-on was supported by Sega.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/segacd.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901015T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/segacda-b.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA CD part A-B</name>
		<desc>SEGA CD part A-B rom set.

History:
The Sega CD, released as the Mega-CD in most regions outside North America, is a CD-ROM accessory for the Sega Genesis video game console designed and produced by Sega$

Seeking to create an add-on device for the Genesis, Sega developed the unit to read compact discs as its storage medium. The main benefit of CD technology was greater $

2.24 million Sega CD units were sold by March 1996, after which the system was officially discontinued as Sega shifted its focus to the Sega Saturn. Retrospective rece$
</desc>
		<image>./icons/segacd.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901015T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/segacdb-c.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA CD part B-C</name>
		<desc>SEGA CD part B-C rom set.

History:
The Sega CD, released as the Mega-CD in most regions outside North America, is a CD-ROM accessory for the Sega Genesis video game console designed and produced by Sega$

Seeking to create an add-on device for the Genesis, Sega developed the unit to read compact discs as its storage medium. The main benefit of CD technology was greater $

2.24 million Sega CD units were sold by March 1996, after which the system was officially discontinued as Sega shifted its focus to the Sega Saturn. Retrospective rece$
</desc>
		<image>./icons/segacd.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901015T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/segacdc-d.sh</path>
		<name>SEGA CD part C-D</name>
		<desc>SEGA CD part C-D rom set.

History:
The Sega CD, released as the Mega-CD in most regions outside North America, is a CD-ROM accessory for the Sega Genesis video game console designed and produced by Sega$

Seeking to create an add-on device for the Genesis, Sega developed the unit to read compact discs as its storage medium. The main benefit of CD technology was greater $

2.24 million Sega CD units were sold by March 1996, after which the system was officially discontinued as Sega shifted its focus to the Sega Saturn. Retrospective rece$
</desc>
		<image>./icons/segacd.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19901015T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/sfc.sh</path>
		<name>Super Famicom</name>
		<desc>Super Famicom. 

History:
The Super Nintendo Entertainment System, and commonly shortened to Super Nintendo is a 16-bit home video game console developed by Nintendo that was released in 1990 in Japan and South Korea, 1991 in North America, 1992 in Europe and Australasia (Oceania), and 1993 in South America. In Japan, the system is called the Super Famicom, officially adopting the abbreviated name of its predecessor, the Famicom, or SFC for short. In South Korea, it is known as the Super Comboy and was distributed by Hyundai Electronics. Although each version is essentially the same, several forms of regional lockout prevent the different versions from being compatible with one another. It was released in Brazil on September 2, 1992, by Playtronic.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sfc.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19900000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/sg-1000.sh</path>
		<name>Sega Computer Videogame SG-1000</name>
		<desc>Sega Computer Videogame SG-1000 rom set. 

History:
The SG-1000, also known as the Sega Computer Videogame SG-1000, is a cartridge-based home video game console manufactured by Sega and released in Japan, Australia, and other countries. It was Sega's first entry into the home video game hardware business, and provided the basis for the more successful Master System. Introduced in 1983, the SG-1000 was released on the same day that Nintendo released the Family Computer (Famicom for short) in Japan. The SG-1000 was released in several forms, including the SC-3000 computer and the redesigned SG-1000 II,[b] also known as the Mark II, released in 1984.

Developed in response to a downturn in arcades in 1982, the SG-1000 was created on the advice of Hayao Nakayama, president of Sega Enterprises, Ltd. Shortly after the release, Sega Enterprises was sold to CSK Corporation, which was followed by the release of the SG-1000 II. Due to the release of the Famicom, and the number of consoles present in the market at the time, the SG-1000 was not commercially successful.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sg-1000_art_blur.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega Enterprises, Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Sega Enterprises, Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/sgfx.sh</path>
		<name>Super Grafx</name>
		<desc>Super Grafx rom set. 

History:
The PC Engine SuperGrafx, also shortened as the SuperGrafx or PC Engine SG, is a video game console by NEC Home Electronics, released exclusively in Japan. It is an upgraded version of the PC Engine, released two years prior. Like the PC Engine, the SuperGrafx was also imported and sold in France.

Originally announced as the PC Engine 2, the machine was purported to be a true 16-bit system with improved graphics and audio capabilities over the original PC Engine. Expected to be released in 1990, the SuperGrafx was rushed to market, debuting several months earlier in late 1989 with only modest improvements over the original PC Engine.

Only seven games were produced which took advantage of the improved SuperGrafx hardware, and two of those could be played on a regular PC Engine. However, the SuperGrafx is backwards compatible with all PC Engine software in both, HuCard and CD-ROM2 format, bringing the compatible software total up to nearly 700. The system was not widely adopted and is largely seen as a commercial failure.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/sgfx.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19891208T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/snes.sh</path>
		<name>Super Nintendo</name>
		<desc>Super Nintendo rom set. 

History:
The SNES is Nintendo's second home console, following the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES). The console introduced advanced graphics and sound capabilities compared with other systems at the time. The development of a variety of enhancement chips integrated in game cartridges helped to keep it competitive in the marketplace.

The SNES was a global success, becoming the best-selling console of the 16-bit era despite its relatively late start and the fierce competition it faced in North America and Europe from Sega's Genesis/Mega Drive console. The SNES remained popular well into the 32-bit era, and continues to be popular among fans, collectors, retro gamers, and emulation enthusiasts, some of whom still make homebrew ROM images.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/snes.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19910823T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/tg16.sh</path>
		<name>TurboGrafx 16</name>
		<desc>TurboGrafx 16 rom set. 

History:
The TurboGrafx-16 Entertainment SuperSystem, known in Japan and France as the PC Engine (Pi Shi Enjin), is a home video game console jointly developed by Hudson Soft and NEC Home Electronics, released in Japan on October 30, 1987 and in the United States on August 29, 1989. It also had a limited release in the United Kingdom and Spain in 1990, known as simply TurboGrafx and based on the American model, whilst the Japanese model was imported and distributed in France in 1989. It was the first console released in the 16-bit era, albeit still utilizing an 8-bit CPU. Originally intended to compete with the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES), it ended up competing with the Sega Genesis, and later on the Super Nintendo Entertainment System (SNES).

The TurboGrafx-16 has an 8-bit CPU, a 16-bit video color encoder, and a 16-bit video display controller. The GPUs are capable of displaying 482 colors simultaneously, out of 512. With dimensions of just 14 cm◊14 cm◊3.8 cm (5.5 in◊5.5 in◊1.5 in), the Japanese PC Engine is the smallest major home game console ever made. Games were stored on a HuCard cartridge, or in CD-ROM optical format with the TurboGrafx-CD add-on.

The TurboGrafx-16 failed to break into the North American market and sold poorly, which has been blamed on inferior marketing. However in Japan the PC Engine was very successful, where it gained strong third-party support and outsold the Famicom at its 1987 debut, eventually becoming the Super Famicom's main rival. Lots of revisions - at least 17 distinct models - were made, such as portable versions and a CD-ROM add-on. A short lived successor, PC Engine SuperGrafx, failed to break through and was quickly discontinued. The entire series was succeeded by the PC-FX in 1994, only released in Japan.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/tg16.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890829T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC Home Electronics Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/vectrex.sh</path>
		<name>Vectrex</name>
		<desc>Vectrex rom set. 

History:
The Vectrex is a vector display-based home video game console that was developed by Western Technologies/Smith Engineering.[1] It was licensed and distributed first by General Consumer Electronics (GCE), and then by Milton Bradley Company after its purchase of GCE. It was released in November 1982 at a retail price of $199 ($480 adjusted for inflation[2]); as Milton Bradley took over international marketing the price dropped to $150, then reduced again to $100 shortly before the video game crash of 1983 and finally retailed at $49 after the crash.[3] The Vectrex exited the console market in early 1984.

Unlike other non-portable video game consoles, which connected to televisions and rendered raster graphics, the Vectrex has an integrated vector monitor which displays vector graphics. The Vectrex is monochrome and uses plastic screen overlays to simulate color and various static graphics and decorations. At the time, many of the most popular arcade games used vector displays, and through a licensing deal with Cinematronics, GCE was able to produce high-quality versions of arcade games such as Space Wars and Armor Attack.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/Vectrex.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19821101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Western Technologies/Smith Engineering</developer>
		<publisher>General Consumer Electronics and Milton Bradley Company</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/videopac2.sh</path>
		<name>Magnavox Odyssey 2 / Videopac 2</name>
		<desc>Magnavox Odyssey 2 / Videopac 2 rom set. 

History:
The Magnavox Odyssey², also known as Philips Odyssey² is a second generation home video game console released in 1978. It was sold in Europe as the Philips Videopac G7000, in Brazil as the Philips Odyssey and in Japan as Odyssey2. Odyssey² was one of the major three home consoles prior to the 1983 video game market crash, along with Atari 2600 and IntelliVision.

In the early 1970s, Magnavox pioneered the home video game industry by successfully bringing the first home console to market, the Odyssey, which was quickly followed by a number of later models, each with a few technological improvements (see Magnavox Odyssey series). In 1978, Magnavox, now a subsidiary of North American Philips, decided to release an all-new successor, Odyssey².

In 2009, the video game website IGN named the Odyssey² the 21st greatest video game console, out of its list of 25
</desc>
		<image>./icons/videopac2.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20041128T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Magnavox</developer>
		<publisher>Magnavox</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/virtualboy.sh</path>
		<name>Virtual Boy</name>
		<desc>Virtual Boy rom set. 

History:
The Virtual Boy is a 32-bit table-top video game console developed and manufactured by Nintendo. Released in 1995, it was marketed as the first console capable of displaying stereoscopic 3D graphics. The player uses the console in a manner similar to a head-mounted display, placing their head against the eyepiece to see a red monochrome display. The games use a parallax effect to create the illusion of depth. Sales failed to meet targets, and by early 1996, Nintendo ceased distribution and game development, only ever releasing 22 games for the system.

Development of the Virtual Boy lasted four years, and began originally under the project name of VR32. Nintendo entered a licensing agreement to utilize a 3D LED eyepiece technology originally developed by U.S.-based company Reflection Technology. It also built a factory in China to be used exclusively for Virtual Boy manufacturing. Over the course of development, the console technology was down-scaled due to high costs and potential health concerns. Furthermore, an increasing amount of company resources were being re-allocated to Nintendo 64 development. Lead Nintendo game designer, Shigeru Miyamoto, had little involvement with the Virtual Boy software. The console was pushed to market in an unfinished state in 1995 to focus on Nintendo 64 development.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/VirtualBoy.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19950000T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/wonderswan.sh</path>
		<name>WonderSwan</name>
		<desc>WonderSwan rom set. 

History:
The WonderSwan is a handheld game console released in Japan by Bandai. It was developed by Gunpei Yokoi's company Koto Laboratory and Bandai, and was the last piece of hardware Yokoi developed before his death in 1997. Released in 1999 in the fifth generation of video game consoles, the WonderSwan and its two later models, the WonderSwan Color and SwanCrystal were officially supported until being discontinued by Bandai in 2003. During its lifespan, no variation of the WonderSwan was released outside of Japan.

Powered by a 16-bit central processing unit, the WonderSwan took advantage of a low price point and long battery life in comparison to its competition, Nintendo's Game Boy Color and SNK's Neo Geo Pocket Color. Later improvements took advantage of quality upgrades to the handheld's screen and added color. The WonderSwan is playable both vertically and horizontally, and features a unique library of games, including numerous first-party titles based on licensed anime properties, as well as significant third-party support from Square, Namco, and Taito.

Overall, the WonderSwan in all its variations combined to sell an estimated 3.5 million units and managed to obtain as much as 8% of the Japanese handheld video game console market before being marginalized by Nintendo's Game Boy Advance. Retrospective feedback praises the potential of the WonderSwan despite its low sales and its brief time holding its own against Nintendo in the marketplace.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/WonderSwan.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19990304T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bandai</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami/full/wonderswancolor.sh</path>
		<name>WonderSwan Color</name>
		<desc>WonderSwan Color rom set.

History:
A redesign of the WonderSwan Color, titled SwanCrystal, was released in Japan on July 12, 2002. Once again, Bandai held a poll on its website to determine casing colors and released the system in blue violet, wine red, crystal blue, and crystal black. Despite its low price and an improved LCD screen, the SwanCrystal was unable to compete, so Bandai announced the discontinuation of the WonderSwan line in 2003 due to low demand and backed out of producing video game hardware altogether. In all, the handheld sold 3.5 million units, of which 1.55 million were of the original WonderSwan and at least 1.1 million were of the WonderSwan Color.
</desc>
		<image>./icons/WonderSwanColor.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>20021712T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bandai</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>home gaming system</genre>
		<playcount />
		<lastplayed />
	</game>
</gameList>
